Thank you for your participation
ご参加ありがとうございます
The hot weather of the summer vacation
夏休みの暑い気候
Then everyone made a special trip to come over and was very touched
それからみんながわざわざわざわざ来てくれて、とても感動していました
that mainly i think
主に私が考えていること
Of course, you may be interested in this topic
もちろん、あなたはこのトピックに興味があるかもしれません
is we put
置いていますか
It is the Laceup key
レースアップキーです
Laceup button
Laceup鍵
Anyway
ともかく
well that's mainly this
まあ主にこれです
How can we in Taipei follow
台北の私たちはどうやってフォローできるでしょうか
Pompeii linked together
つながったポンペイ
Well, in fact, especially in recent years
そうですね、実際、特にここ数年は
We do a lot of work on the mainland site
私たちは本土の現場で多くの仕事をしています
Of course, this world happens to have
もちろん、この世界にはたまたま
Pompeii film in 2014 also
2014年のポンペイ映画も
also played
も遊んだ
So the whole world is especially Taiwanese
つまり全世界が特に台湾人なのです
Notice
注意
In fact, there are actually many topics for such a topic.
実はこのような話題はたくさんあります。
My colleagues or some friends say that my topic is too sensational
同僚や友人が私の話題がセンセーショナルすぎると言っています
So you give this title
だからあなたはこのタイトルを付けます
Just to trick everyone
みんなを騙すためだけに
Actually this topic is not
実はこの話題はそうではない
I shouldn't have given it to you
あなたにあげるべきではなかった
Conversely, because I did work on the Continental War
逆に、私は大陸戦争に取り組んでいたので、
So I go to many places, no matter assisting speeches or popular science speeches
だから私は補助スピーチや大衆科学スピーチに関係なく、多くの場所に行きます。
In fact, after most of the speeches, people will come to me and ask me
実際、ほとんどのスピーチの後、人々は私のところに来て尋ねます。
Will Taipei become Pompeii?
台北はポンペイになるのか？
So this is something that a lot of people care about
これは多くの人が気にしていることです
then i hope today this
それなら今日はこれを願っています
more than an hour of these materials
これらの資料を 1 時間以上
After sharing with you, I think everyone will have the answer
皆さんと共有すれば、誰もが答えを得ることができると思います
This very clear answer must be presented
この非常に明確な答えを提示する必要があります
especially in recent months
特にここ数ヶ月
Last one or two years
ここ1、2年
we'll start with this
これから始めます
At the end of last year, the Legislative Yuan
昨年末、立法院は
volcanic disaster
火山災害
Natural disasters like earthquakes, typhoons, floods, etc.
台湾に及ぶ地震、台風、洪水などの自然災害
add volcanic disaster
火山災害を追加する
But everyone knows this is a new thing
しかし、これが新しいことであることは誰もが知っています
the past was never
過去は決してなかった
That's because the Legislative Yuan passed this amendment
それは立法院がこの修正案を可決したからです
Therefore, the Executive Yuan and local governments have taken many related actions.
したがって、行政院と地方政府は多くの関連措置を講じてきた。
that's especially taipei
それは特に台北です
The volcanic disaster that Taipei also practiced at the end of March this year
今年3月末に台北でも起きた火山災害
Especially for the residents of Beitou and Tianmu under Yangming Mountain
特に陽明山の麓の北投と天母の住民にとっては
let them know in case of volcanic activity
火山活動の場合は知らせてください
how to deal with
対処方法
Because in the history of mankind we Taiwan
なぜなら人類の歴史の中で私たち台湾は
but no volcanic disaster
でも火山災害はなかった
The Philippines, Japan, Indonesia around us
私たちの周りのフィリピン、日本、インドネシア
In fact, there are volcanic disasters at both ends of the three days
実は3日間の両端で火山災害が発生しています。
Both their people and the government have some ideas about how to deal with it
国民も政府も、それに対処する方法についていくつかのアイデアを持っています
But Taiwan is really strange
でも台湾って本当に変だよ
So hopefully we know more about the hazards of this volcano
この火山の危険性についてもっと学ぶことができれば幸いです
especially in recent months
特にここ数ヶ月
Volcanoes this May in Hawaii
今年5月にハワイで起きた火山
The dragon smoke flow is on the road
龍の煙の流れが道にある
Everyone knows that Dragon Mist
ドラゴンの煙が流れることは誰もが知っています
It's very hot and very scary
とても暑くてとても怖いです
Anything that touches it will be completely destroyed.
それに触れるものはすべて完全に破壊されます。
Then if you go to Google and read a lot of reports like this
次に、Google にアクセスしてこのようなレポートをたくさん読んでみると、
Whether it's a direct dragon smoke stream
龍煙直流なのか
Or some breathing or toxic gas
あるいは呼吸や有毒ガス
There are actually many kinds
実はたくさんの種類があります
In fact, here I would like to point out the following
実は、ここで次のことを指摘しておきたいと思います。
This time, the eruption of this volcano
今回のこの火山の噴火は、
Caused a 6.9 earthquake
マグニチュード6.9の地震を引き起こした
That's actually science
それはまさに科学です
Or quite a lot of people are quite curious
あるいは、かなり多くの人が非常に興味を持っています
Do volcanoes cause earthquakes?
火山は地震を引き起こすのでしょうか？
Not only this time in Hawaii
今回のハワイに限らず、
The volcanic eruption in 1975
1975年の火山噴火
Also triggered a larger 7.1 earthquake
さらに大きなマグニチュード7.1の地震も引き起こした
So what's the point of this?
それで、これには何の意味があるのでしょうか？
In fact, if you are interested in earth science or Taiwan
実際、地球科学や台湾に興味があるなら
If there are some concepts of these geology in northern Taiwan
台湾北部にこのような地質の概念があるとしたら
In fact, you will think of what is next to the volcano on the mainland
実際、本土の火山の隣に何があるかを考えるでしょう。
We actually have quite a few foothill faults that seismologists worry about
実際、地震学者が心配している丘陵断層がかなりの数あります。
Then someone talked about volcanic activity
それから誰かが火山活動について話しました
Could it be something like the event that triggered the Foothill Fault?
それはフットヒル断層を引き起こした出来事のようなものでしょうか？
The foothills fault in the evaluation of experts and scholars
専門家や学者の評価における麓の欠陥
If this dislocation of the entire fault at the foot of the mountain
この山麓の断層全体がずれると、
The earthquake that is likely to be triggered is about 6.5 to 6.6
引き起こされる可能性のある地震はマグニチュード6.5～6.6程度
Although not very big compared with this
これに比べるとそれほど大きくないですが、
But it's on the fringe of metropolis Taipei
しかし、ここは大都市台北の外れにあります
In fact, according to the evaluation of the International Earthquake Company Center
実際、国際地震企業センターの評価によれば、
If the fault at the foot of the mountain is active
山の麓の断層が活動している場合
Thousands of houses in Taipei may collapse
台北の数千の家屋が倒壊の可能性
Of course thousands of lives were lost
もちろん何千人もの命が失われた
it's potentially dangerous
それは潜在的に危険です
Of course, this is the relationship between outer volcanoes and earthquakes
もちろん、これは外火山と地震の関係です
volcanoes cause earthquakes
火山は地震を引き起こす
Earthquakes trigger volcanoes
地震は火山を引き起こす
But it doesn't have to be a matter of incentives
しかし、それはインセンティブの問題である必要はありません
in some cases there will be
場合によってはあるでしょう
The summer fish activity in May
5月の夏魚アクティビティ
volcanic activity
火山活動
On June 2nd, Gualimara in Central and South America
6月2日、中南米グアリマラ
This is also the scene of the volcano
ここも火山の光景です
There can be these lava flows, debris flows, mudflows
溶岩流、土石流、泥流が発生する可能性があります
Then look at the volcanic eruption of summer fish
それから夏魚の火山噴火を見てください
from the past few decades
過去数十年から
hardly a single life was lost
命が失われることはほとんどなかった
But compared to Central and South America
でも中南米に比べると
Look at this a volcanic eruption
見てください、これは火山の噴火です
dozens of people died
数十人が死亡した
hundreds of people missing
数百人が行方不明
Most of that believed to be missing
そのほとんどが失われていると考えられている
Roughly equal to the number of deaths
死者数とほぼ同じ
then you can see
そうすればわかります
This Central and South American and summer fish
中南米と夏の魚です
why such a big difference
なぜこれほど大きな違いがあるのか
In addition to the difference in volcanic characteristics
火山の性質の違いに加えて
actually very important very important what is
実はとても重要です とても重要です
This summer fish has done a lot of work
この夏の魚たちはたくさんの仕事をしてくれました
Japan has done a lot
日本は多くのことをしてきた
Volcanoes like Japan are often erupting
日本のような火山は頻繁に噴火します
But the threat to human life
しかし人命への脅威
really very few
本当にとても少ないです
That
それか
Like this June, Sakurajima Volcano is erupting
今年の6月と同じように桜島火山が噴火しています
Of course, this dragon is flowing, because Sakurajima is across the sea
もちろん、この龍が流れているのは、海の向こうに桜島があるからです。
So there is actually no direct dragon smoke flow, broken hole flow, or threat to this city.
つまり、実際には、直接的な龍煙の流れも、壊れた穴の流れも、この都市への脅威もありません。
But volcanic ash is actually causing a lot of trouble, too.
しかし、火山灰は実際に多くの問題も引き起こしています。
Then this Bali Island, Bali Island in Indonesia
それからこのバリ島、インドネシアのバリ島です。
This is also the last volcanic activity at the end of June
これは6月末の最後の火山活動でもあります
Then some of the things that caused the tourist crowds
次に、観光客の混雑を引き起こしたいくつかのこと
Well, I'm actually going to tell a little story about this.
さて、実際にこれについて少しお話します。
It's the end of June this year
今年も6月末ですね
In fact, Agong Volcano was in October last year
実はアゴン火山は昨年10月に
If everyone has an impression, he also sprayed it once
皆さんも印象に残っていたら彼も一度スプレーしてみました
Then this was two months before the eruption of Agong Volcano
それからこれはアゴン火山の噴火の2か月前でした
One day I arrived at the office at 8 o'clock in the morning
ある日、朝8時過ぎに会社に到着しました
I got a call from this certain reporter, a reporter from the radio station.
ある記者、ラジオ局の記者から電話がありました。
He called and said, Teacher Lin, hello, I'm Momo reporter
彼は電話して、「リンさん、こんにちは、モモ記者です」と言いました。
Who, who, actually, I can't remember
誰、誰、実は思い出せない
Well, it's really because of too many reporters.
まあ、それは本当に記者が多すぎるからです。
Then I said yes yes I remembered
それから私は「はい、はい、思い出しました」と言いました
He said let me ask you a question
彼は、質問させてくださいと言った
I said I thought there was another news
私は別のニュースがあると思うと言いました
He said no no it was a personal accident
彼は「いいえ、いいえ、それは人身事故です」と言いました
The reason is that he is going to Paris Island
理由はパリス島に行くから
He's celebrating his 25th birthday
彼は25歳の誕生日を迎えています
Because those friends are going to Paris Island to play
その友達がパリス島に遊びに行くから
As a result, when he was going
その結果、彼が行ったとき、
Paris Island announced that the volcano had started quasi-motion
パリ島は火山が擬似運動を始めたと発表した
Then he called me and asked me if I wanted to go
それから彼は私に電話して、行きたいかどうか尋ねました
then i will talk to him
それから私は彼と話します
This Indonesian survey
今回のインドネシア調査
Because I don't have the data
データがないので
I don't understand very clearly
あまりはっきりとはわかりません
but i told him
でも私は彼に言いました
if you are not in such a hurry
そんなに急いでいないのであれば
you may wait a little while
少しお待ちください
After Indonesia or the official announcement
インドネシアまたは公式発表後
then you have to judge
それならあなたが判断しなければなりません
Then he probably listened to me
そうしたら彼はおそらく私の話を聞いてくれたでしょう
just two months
たった2ヶ月
another morning
別の朝
he called again
他又打電話
I'm Mongolian reporter
私はモンゴル人記者です
He said sorry for me now
彼は今、私に申し訳ないと言いました
Now at Zhongzheng Airport
現在中正空港にいます
the night before
夜になる前に
waited for two months
2ヶ月待ちました
Volcano finally erupts to the surface
火山がついに地表に噴火
He said, should I go?
彼は、「行った方がいいですか？」と言いました。
really two months
本当に2ヶ月
I said you are amazing
あなたはすごいって言いました
The flight was delayed just in time for the volcanic eruption
飛行機は火山の噴火に間に合うように遅れた
Then I told him that you might go
それから私は彼に、あなたが行ってもよいと言いました
Maybe there will be a delay at the airport like this
もしかしたらこのまま空港で遅延が起きるかもしれない
But because
しかし理由は
The one that erupted from Grandpa Volcano
おじいちゃん火山から噴出したもの
This Paris Island tourist place is about 60 kilometers away
このパリ島の観光地は約 60 キロ離れています
Maybe the volcano will have some impact on the airport
おそらく火山は空港に何らかの影響を与えるでしょう
But at least the safety of your life should be nothing
でも、少なくともあなたの命の安全は何でもないはずです
scruples
遠慮する
so he went
それで彼は行きました
so what does this represent
それで、これはどういう意味ですか
In fact, the volcano does not come instantly
実際、火山はすぐに起こるわけではありません
unlike an earthquake
地震と違って
We can't predict earthquakes yet.
地震はまだ予知できません。
when will you come
いつ来ますか
no one can tell
誰も言えない
But volcanoes basically
でも火山って基本的には
like just said
今言ったように
this japan america
この日本アメリカ
or these
またはこれら
They can actually warn you by doing some observation techniques
彼らはいくつかの観察テクニックを実行することで実際に警告することができます
He started moving purely
彼は純粋に動き始めた
You may have to prepare or do something
準備や何かをする必要があるかもしれません
So overall
全体的に見て
In fact, the simplest way is to say
実際、最も簡単な方法はこう言うことです
You may well imagine that
よく想像できるかもしれませんが、
this is our taipei
ここが私たちの台北です
this is 101
これは101です
This is me climbing to the top of the Nine-Five Peak
これは九五峰の頂上に登る私です
took a photo
写真を撮りました
Then I put this
それからこれを置きました
The ancient city of Pompeii covered the Seven Star Mountain
七星山を覆った古代都市ポンペイ
will it be like this
こうなるだろうか
It's something that many people imagine
それは多くの人が想像することです
then we want to talk today
それでは今日は話したいと思います
Pompeii and Taipei
ポンペイと台北
or this
またはこれ
The Great Looming Volcano
迫り来る巨大な火山
Vesvi
ヴェスヴィ
do some comparisons
いくつか比較してみよう
what does he have the same
彼が同じものを持っているのは何ですか
how is he different
彼はどう違うの？
then we know
そうすればわかります
what will happen to him
彼に何が起こるでしょうか
So according to this very simple introduction
したがって、この非常に簡単な紹介によると、
I probably have six of these
多分これ6個持ってる
Let me tell you about this
これについてお話しましょう
The first, of course, is nothing more than
もちろん、最初のものは以上のものではありません
Let me introduce the relationship between Pompeii and Vesvi
ポンペイとヴェスヴィの関係を紹介します。
We all know each other well
私たちは皆お互いのことをよく知っています
Maybe some people are a little blurry
少しぼやけてる人もいるかもしれない
Let us now briefly introduce the space-time background
ここで時空の背景を簡単に紹介しましょう
let everyone know a little bit
みんなに少し知らせて
And the main part is to say
そして肝心な部分はこう言うことです
when the volcano erupts
火山が噴火するとき
Why did it cause the entire city of Pompeii
なぜポンペイ市全体が破壊されたのか
the whole is submerged
全体が水没している
what kind of disaster it has
どのような災害があるのか
By the way we introduce it
ちなみに紹介するのは
Then the second is
それから 2 つ目は、
Taipei and Datong volcanoes
台北と大同の火山
Just now the vice president also said
今副社長も言ってた
it's a volcano
それは火山です
In fact, this is what we have done in the past ten years
実際、これが私たちが過去 10 年間に行ってきたことです
Some of our like-minded friends in the academic world
学術界の志を同じくする友人たち
Results from different observations
さまざまな観察から得られた結果
it looks like a volcano
火山のように見えます
That's especially my own work on this magma chamber
特にこのマグマ貯蔵庫に関する私自身の作品です
It actually took me a lot of time
実はかなり時間がかかりました
Sometimes I'm embarrassed to speak in private
プライベートで話すのが恥ずかしいこともあります
In ancient times, I heard people say
昔、人々がこう言うのを聞いたことがあります。
Grind one piece in this decade
この10年で一枚を磨く
I have that deep feeling
そういう深い思いがあるんだよ
I spent more than ten years
10年以上を費やしました
finally put
やっと入れた
Want to Answer Questions Do Some Find Some Answers
質問に答えたい 何かをして答えを見つけよう
The fourth part is TVO
第四部はTVO
This aunt volcano is alive with this aunt volcano
この火山おばさんはこの火山おばさんとともに生きている
and threatening
そして脅迫する
But it's not such a scary thing
でもそんな怖いものじゃないよ
as long as we are ready
私たちの準備ができている限り
That preparation is actually based on scientific monitoring
その準備は実際には科学的なモニタリングに基づいています
scientific knowledge
科学的知識
In fact, it can provide us with many ways to deal with
実際、それは私たちに対処する多くの方法を提供します
that fifth part is fun
その5部は楽しいです
This is not for fun
これは楽しむためのものではありません
for me personally
私個人にとって
I studied ninth science
私は9番目の科学を勉強しました
And it specializes in the study of earthquakes.
そして、それは地震の研究を専門としています。
When I saw the place name of this volcano
この火山の地名を見たとき
Heartbeat with the Volcano
火山の鼓動
I'm really an official
実は公務員なんです
That heartbeat like a volcano
火山のような鼓動
I believe no one in the world has seen
世界中で誰も見たことがないと思います
when i first saw
初めて見たとき
I don't think there is such a thing
そんな事ないと思うよ
I will report to you later
後ほどご報告させていただきます
Finally, a summary and discussion
最後にまとめと考察
So I'm just posting this
だから私はこれを投稿しているだけです
Explain to everyone one by one
全員に一つ一つ説明していきます
Let's talk about Pompeii first
まずはポンペイについて話しましょう
Vivo Hill
ビボヒル
the italian peninsula
イタリア半島
Rome
ローマ
Then to the south of it is
するとその南にあるのが、
next to the ancient city
古代都市の隣
Next to the ancient city is the volcano Vesuvius
古代都市の隣にはヴェスヴィオ火山があります
that feeling is
その気持ちは
the roman empire was very
ローマ帝国はとても素晴らしかった
when very strong
とても強いとき
The economy is very good in all aspects
経済はあらゆる面で非常に良好です
actually
実際
many have
多くの人が持っています
accomplished or
達成したり、
VIP is simple VIP
VIPは単なるVIPです
It will be next to the ancient city here
ここの古代都市の隣になります
to buy a villa
別荘を買うために
just come here for vacation
ただ休暇のためにここに来てください
why come here for vacation
なぜ休暇にここに来るのですか
In fact, the world probably
実際、おそらく世界は、
There are such phenomena
そういう現象もあるんですね
Near the volcano are the most
火山の近くが最も多い
most beautiful
もっとも美しい
like tokyo in japan
像日本的東京
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
Next to Mount Fuji
富士山の隣
about 60 kilometers
約60キロ
that's japanese
それは日本人です
spirit or fly to a place where it is not possible
精神を失うか、不可能な場所に飛ぶか
that's actually like
それは実際に似ています
Then he came back to Taipei
それから彼は台北に戻ってきました
Taipei
台北
where will this rich man be
この金持ちはどこにいるのだろうか
You have to support yourself to build some mansions, right?
豪邸を建てるには自活しなければなりませんよね？
Because there are mountains and water
山と水があるから
just beautiful
ただただ美しい
so like
以下のようなので
As long as there are volcanoes in the world
世界に火山がある限り
basically just pretty
基本的にただかわいいだけ
that is
あれは
It's a place that makes you feel comfortable
気持ちが楽になる場所です
but
しかし
Of course he has his threats
もちろん彼には脅しがある
2000 years ago
2000年前
The science of course is almost zero
もちろん科学はほぼゼロです
so they also
だから彼らも
didn't expect these things
こういったことは期待していませんでした
so right here
だからここで
built this ancient city
この古代都市を建設しました
If you have the opportunity to go now
今行く機会があれば
or have the opportunity to
またはその機会がある
This is Vizvi
ヴィズヴィです
This is the current appearance of the ancient city
これが古代都市の現在の姿です
After everyone is excavated
全員発掘したら
The rest becomes a
残りは
Very
非常
very this
とてもこれ
one for many people to visit
多くの人が訪れるための場所
a museum
一個博物館
or attractions
またはアトラクション
Then of course the result of this is
そしてもちろん、この結果は次のようになります
When Vizvi volcano erupted
ヴィズビ火山が噴火したとき
take this
これを取る
This is from the movie
これは映画からのものです
the plot is
プロットは
The entire ancient city of Pangbei will be covered.
古代都市龐北全体がカバーされます。
Then review these relevant knowledge
次に、これらの関連知識を確認してください
this
これ
Visvi and Pombe
ヴィスヴィとポンベ
In fact, Weisvi is in the ancient city of Pompei to the south of him
実際、ワイスヴィは彼の南にある古代都市ポンペイにいます。
About 10 kilometers away
約10キロ離れたところ
The gray one means that
灰色のものは次のことを意味します
volcanic ash
火山灰
When the volcano erupted, the volcanic ash covered the entire area.
火山が噴火したとき、火山灰がその地域全体を覆いました。
so in
それで
During the eruption in 2000, the entire ancient city of Pompei was covered with 6 meters of volcanic ash
2000 年の噴火では、古代都市ポンペイ全体が 6 メートルの火山灰で覆われました。
In fact, nothing is gone
実際には何もなくなっていない
That
それか
The survey at the time said that there were probably
当時の調査によると、おそらく
20,000 people live in Pombe
ポンベには2万人が住んでいる
And what is the emphasis on
そして何に重点を置いているのか
in the holiday villa
別荘で
Everyone is relaxing over there
あそこではみんなくつろいでいます
on vacation
休暇中
It was not until the 16th century when the canal was opened
運河が開通したのは 16 世紀になってからです
Found an ancient wall but
古代の壁を見つけましたが、
to this
これに
In the 18th century, the king wanted to have these ancient arts
18世紀、これらの古代芸術を手に入れるために、王は
young cause
若い大義
So he spent a lot of money to put this street in Pompey
それで彼はポンペイウスにこの通りを作るために多額のお金を費やしました
A lot of antiquities, just dig it out
骨董品がたくさんあるので、掘り出してみましょう
That's why people know
だからこそ人々は知っている
Oh, this used to be a very big city
ああ、ここは昔はとても大きな街でした
Although only twenty thousand
たった2万だけど
But you can imagine 20,000 people two thousand years ago
しかし、2000年前の2万人の人々を想像することはできます。
It's a very lively city
とても活気のある街です
Then they dug this
それから彼らはこれを掘ります
You see, the streets are very well planned
ご存知の通り、街路は非常によく計画されています
worthy of work
仕事に値する
and especially this
そして特にこれ
This one has a giant merchant's house above it
ここの上には巨大な商家がある
It will say on the ground, this money
それは地上で言うだろう、このお金は
This welcome money welcomes you
このウェルカムマネーはあなたを歓迎します
It means they are extravagant
それは彼らが贅沢であることを意味します
In fact, go to Google to find this literature theory
実際、この文学理論を見つけるには Google にアクセスしてください
There are many criticisms
批判もたくさんあるよ
It was the luxury of the life of the Romans at that time
それは当時のローマ人の生活の贅沢でした
Or a lot of negative words are in it
もしくはネガティブな言葉が多く含まれている
Then of course the last
それからもちろん最後は
They don't know the money is waiting for you
彼らはお金があなたを待っていることを知りません
But the volcano is there too
でも火山もそこにある
In fact, two sides of the same body
実は、同じ体の表裏が
Then why did this happen in the end?
では、結局なぜこうなったのでしょうか？
This is what we want to convey to you
これが私たちがあなたに伝えたいことです
What kind of threat does the volcano pose to me?
火山は私にとってどのような脅威をもたらしますか?
Then this is the original
それでは、これがオリジナルです
These residents were instantly overwhelmed by high temperature
これらの住民はすぐに高熱に襲われました
When pyroclastic volcanoes are buried
火砕火山が埋もれるとき
In fact, your bone and flesh tissue is gone in an instant.
実際、骨や肉の組織は一瞬にして失われてしまいます。
But your body becomes hollow
でも体は空洞になってしまう
This is because they poured plaster into it
これは石膏を流し込んだためです
look like people at that time
当時の人に似てる
helped it out
それを助けてくれた
why is that so
どうしてこんなことに
In fact, I want to introduce to you
実は、皆さんにご紹介したいのが、
this pyroclastic
この火砕流
this is real
これは本物です
Because Pompeii in the 2000s
2000年代のポンペイだから
There is no way to testify
証言する方法がない
But volcanic activity
でも火山活動は
In fact, there will always be
実際には、常に存在します
crumbs
パン粉
What does this photo look like?
この写真は何に見えますか?
Super like this sand leopard
このスナヒョウにとても似ています
Anyway, it's just a cloud of ashes.
とにかく、それはただの灰の雲です。
so you can't see what you're wearing
だから何を着ているか見えない
But this is totally different from the Dust Leopard
しかし、これはダストレオパードとはまったく異なります
Dust Leopard, look at this speed is very fast
Dust Leopard、見てください、このスピードはとても速いです
100 kilometers per hour 200 kilometers per hour
時速100キロメートル 時速200キロメートル
Then this is very hot
それから、これはとても暑いです
hundreds of degrees of high temperature
数百度の高温
It means you can't escape
つまり逃げられないということだ
if you are touched by it
もしあなたがそれに感動したら
In fact, probably like the inhabitants of Pompeii
実際、おそらくポンペイの住民と同じだろう
almost identical
ほぼ同じ
so you see this
それでこれを見ます
These are some village houses on the hillside
これらは丘の中腹にあるいくつかの村の家です
Actually you can imagine this
実はこれは想像できる
In fact, there will be nothing left
実際には何も残らないだろう
would have exactly the same result as Pompeii.
ポンペイと全く同じ結果になるだろう。
then this is all real
それならこれは全部本当だよ
This is a Filipino brand
こちらはフィリピンのブランドです
when my volcano erupts
私の火山が噴火したとき
you can see
見ることができます
There's one in the lower left corner, a little bit of a truck
左下隅にトラックのようなものがあります
see this stream
このストリームを参照してください
certainly
そうです
Run if you can run, jump into a car if you can
走れるなら走って、走れるなら車に飛び乗ろう
run fast
速く走る
But like I just said, can these people escape?
しかし、先ほども言いましたが、この人たちは逃げられるのでしょうか？
Basically, you can't run away, because the speed of this broken hole is faster than the car on Gao Ai Nurse Highway
この壊れた穴の速度はガオアイナースハイウェイの車よりも速いため、基本的に逃げることはできません
What's more, this is a path in the field
しかもここは畑の中の小道
That
それか
Also in the same year, this silvery volcano in Japan
同じ年に、日本のこの銀色の火山も
You can google this, you can see this video
これをGoogleで検索すると、このビデオが表示されます
He is here, the car is here, and when he sees the broken hole, run quickly
彼はここにいます、車はここにあります、そして壊れた穴を見ると彼は急いで走ります
Then the broken hole flow keeps coming and going, and then
その後、壊れた穴の流れが行ったり来たりを繰り返し、
The screen goes black, and then why do I see
画面が真っ暗になりますが、なぜ表示されるのでしょうか
Later, people took this camera and put it
その後、人々はこのカメラを取り上げて設置しました
Take it out, since that record is still there
その記録はまだ残っているので取り出してください
he played it back
彼はそれを再生した
Then restore it to the process at that time
その後、その時点のプロセスに復元します
So the cavitation flow is actually for volcanic disasters, it is
つまり、キャビテーションの流れは実際には火山災害のためのものです。
first place
最初の場所
It's hard to guard against, and you probably won't be able to run away when you see it
ガードが難しくて、見たら逃げられないかもしれない
it's very very scary
とてもとても怖いです
Then why are there crumbs? There is a very simple cartoon explanation diagram for this
では、なぜパンくずが存在するのでしょうか?これについては、非常に簡単な漫画の説明図があります。
Because when the magma keeps coming up from the crater
マグマが火口から湧き続けるから
That's a thousand-degree high-temperature thing
それは千度の高温のものです
After coming straight up, it's starting to cool down a bit after this side
まっすぐ登ってきたのに、この辺から少し涼しくなってきました
But still a few hundred degrees left
でもまだ数百度残っている
but it starts off kind of turning into something solid
でも、それは何かしっかりしたものに変わり始めます
It just turns into stone energy, and it will feel a little cooling down slowly
石のエネルギーになって少しずつ冷めていく感じ
But when it keeps piling up
でもそれが積み重なっていくと
Because of gravity, it will eventually collapse
重力のせいでいつかは崩れてしまう
so when it accumulates a lot
だからそれがたくさん溜まると
When it collapsed in an instant, a debris flow was generated
一瞬にして崩れると土石流が発生
Underneath are small stones or these large and small stones
その下には小さな石、またはこれらの大小の石があります
There's volcanic ash on it, and it's all down
火山灰が積もっていて、全部落ちている
So this is the one that threatens the most
つまり、これが最も脅威となるのです
And what I just said is because of the high temperature
そして今言ったのは気温が高いからです
Look at this, as soon as you get down, the whole house burns down
見てください、あなたが降りるとすぐに家全体が燃えてしまいます
which one is the most
どれが一番多いですか
The most modern, and the best example of this, is the Ginsen Volcano in Japan
最も現代的でその最良の例は、日本の銀泉火山です。
This is the eruption of this Yinxian volcano
これがこの銀県火山の噴火です
Then this is Shimabara Temple, just at the foot of the mountain
さて、こちらが山の麓にある島原寺です。
And then this tax leak comes from this hilltop
そして、この税金漏洩はこの丘の上から発生します
Just go down the whole valley
谷全体を下っていくだけです
So what happened?
どうしたの？
an arrow like this
こんな矢印です
This is a tax leak, just go down this valley
これは税金の漏洩です、この谷を下ってください
The one that digs low is like a river
低く掘るものは川のようだ
So the main tax stones
それで、主な税金の石は
that would go along these low valleys
それはこれらの低い谷に沿って進むでしょう
but here it takes a turn
しかし、ここで方向転換します
turn these stones
これらの石を回してください
it's heavier, it goes this way
重いよ、こっちに行くよ
But what does this one arrow represent?
しかし、この一本の矢印は何を表しているのでしょうか？
It's just ash, a lighter substance
それは単なる灰であり、より軽い物質です
it has no friction against the ground
地面との摩擦がありません
It's coming straight from here, right here
ここからまっすぐ来ます、ここから
Then rush over here is the village
じゃあ急いでこっちに村だ
There is a primary school in the village
村には小学校があります
Let's see what's going on in this elementary school
この小学校で何が起こっているのか見てみましょう
this is this
これはこれです
This crumb came from here
このパン粉はここから来ました
so we are
だから私たちは
crumbs have from this
パン粉はこれからあります
Come over from the back of the classroom
教室の後ろから来てください
Of course you can see the glass
もちろんガラスも見えます
all
全部都
by that
それによって
those with crumbs
パン粉のあるもの
break it apart
それを壊す
Whole
全体
but if you look
でも見てみると
the other side
向こう側
what can you see
なにが見えますか
this is
これは
Lee doors and windows
リーのドアと窓
You can imagine how hot that temperature is
その気温がどれほど暑いか想像できるでしょう
That's volcanic ash
それは火山灰です
that hundreds of degrees of temperature
その数百度の温度
come in an instant
すぐに来てください
Li Menchuang
李夢荘
That's the same temperature
それは同じ温度です
deformed throughout
全体的に変形している
so you imagine saying this thing
だからあなたはこんなことを言うのを想像します
very hot stuff
とても熱いもの
Li doors and windows are deformed
ドアや窓が変形している
you can imagine people
あなたは人々を想像することができます
or all these houses
あるいはこれらすべての家
General traditional wooden or house
一般の伝統的な木造または住宅
It burns in an instant
一瞬で燃え上がる
That's actually
それは実際に
Silver Circle volcano on top of history
歴史の頂点に立つシルバー サークル火山
In fact, for Japan
実は日本にとって
very, very many hard lessons
とても、とてもたくさんの難しいレッスン
this 1792
これは1792年
Fifteen thousand deaths from this
これにより15,000人が死亡
why hundreds of years ago
なぜ何百年も前に
This is actually a worthwhile
これは実際に価値があります
One of these natural disasters around the world
世界中で起きている自然災害のひとつ
This model of understanding
この理解モデル
then how could this be
ではどうしてこれがあり得るのか
That's when the volcano erupted
そのとき火山が噴火した
Just like the eruption of Xiahaoyi volcano just now
ちょうど今の夏葵火山の噴火のように
cause an earthquake of about seven
マグニチュード7程度の地震を引き起こす
Then this earthquake of course the damage of the earthquake
それでは今回の地震はもちろん地震の被害も
we can imagine
私たちは想像できます
even more frightening
さらに恐ろしい
He put the other side of this silver announcement
彼はこの銀の宣言の裏側を述べた
there was a mountain
山がありました
shake it all down
すべてを振り下ろして
He just slides into the sea
彼はただ海に滑り込むだけだ
If it slips into the sea, it will generate a tsunami
海に滑り込むと津波が発生する
So this typical
したがって、この典型的な
A compound disaster is a volcano, an earthquake, three eruptions and a tsunami
複合災害とは、火山、地震、3 つの噴火、津波のことです。
15,000 people
15,000人
probably more than ten thousand people
おそらく1万人以上
They all died from the impact of this tsunami
この津波の影響で全員が亡くなりました
Then this is Yinxuan Volcano in Kyushu
さて、こちらは九州の銀仙火山です
he is here
彼はここにいます
So you see this to this landslide to
それで、これがこの地滑りに見られるでしょう
Ocean
海
In fact, all the residents of the surrounding seaside villages in the Inner Sea suffered disaster.
実際、瀬戸内海の周囲の海辺の村の住民は皆、被害を受けています。
That's why there are so many casualties
だからこれだけの犠牲者が出るんだよ
So the Fowles disaster is now more familiar to everyone.
そのため、ファウルズの災害は今では誰にとってもより身近なものとなっています。
Like Japan's Three World Wars and One Earthquake
日本の3度の世界大戦と1度の地震のように
We all know about earthquakes, tsunamis, river disasters
地震、津波、河川災害については誰もが知っています。
River disasters may actually be more beautiful and perfect than earthquakes and tsunamis
河川災害は実際には地震や津波よりも美しく完璧なのかもしれない
So that is to say, from the very beginning of this event
つまり、このイベントの最初から
In fact, the most serious thing is the last one
最後まで原因がある、実際、最も深刻なのは最後だ
So the Fuers disaster is actually relevant to what we are talking about now.
つまり、このフュエルスの災害は、実は私たちが今話していることに関連しているのです。
This disaster prevention is very important
この防災はとても大切です
if i know soon what's going on with this
これで何が起こっているのかすぐにわかれば
I have time to avoid subsequent actions
その後の行動を避ける時間がある
or some disaster
あるいは何らかの災害
Therefore, Fuers disaster is a very important concept for disaster prevention in the world.
したがって、フュエル災害は世界の防災にとって非常に重要な概念です。
Well, let's talk about this same thing, which of course hasn't happened yet.
さて、これと同じことについて話しましょう。もちろん、それはまだ起こっていません。
This is what many American advanced European scientists worry about
これは多くのアメリカの先進的なヨーロッパの科学者が懸念していることです
This is Africa This is North America South America
ここはアフリカです ここは北アメリカ 南アメリカです
On the west coast of Africa there is a volcanic island
アフリカの西海岸に火山島がある
volcanic islands likewise they serve as
火山島も同様に機能します
When the volcano erupts, the volcanic island will collapse
火山が噴火すると火山島は崩壊する
or these very steep terrain
またはこの非常に険しい地形
As long as it collapses, there will be a tsunami
崩れる限り津波が来る
Then the scientist is free to do some simulations
その後、科学者は自由にいくつかのシミュレーションを行うことができます
but scary
でも怖い
look at these numbers
これらの数字を見てください
it's 132 meters
132メートルです
Which city or 132 us if
どこの都市か 132 私たちなら
In Shancheng Princess, we may all soak in the sea here
山城公主では、ここでみんなで海に浸かるかもしれません
inside sea water
海水の中
That
それか
Although in the west of Africa
アフリカの西にありますが、
But New York and Boston in the United States
でもアメリカのニューヨークとボストンは
or many cities on the east coast
または東海岸の多くの都市
As long as this tsunami comes
この津波が来る限り
This is really out of hand
これは本当に手に負えない
It is a great threat to mankind and the United States
それは人類と米国にとって大きな脅威です
Will this be a serious problem?
これは深刻な問題になりますか?
Now none of us can tell
今では誰もそれを言うことはできません
but what day is the real volcanic activity
しかし、本当の火山活動は何日ですか
become a disaster caused by a tsunami
津波による災害になる
is a question worth thinking about
考える価値のある質問です
Although every week in Africa seems to have nothing to do with us
アフリカでの毎週のことは私たちとは何の関係もないように思えますが、
I especially take the opportunity to point out
私は特に指摘する機会を利用しています
That is to say, everyone knows about Guishan Island.
つまり亀山島は誰もが知っているということです。
I didn't talk about Guishan Island today
今日は亀山島の話をしませんでした
But Guishan Island is outside the Big Butt Volcano
しかし、亀山島はビッグバット火山の外にあります
volcanically active volcanic island in taiwan
台湾の火山活動が活発な火山島
If you have been to Guishan Island
亀山島に行ったことがある方は
You can see that these terrains are very steep
この地形が非常に険しいことがわかります
If a volcanic event takes this piece
火山活動がこの作品を奪ったら
array it like this
このように配列します
This is of course a simulation
もちろんシミュレーションです
It also creates waves or tsunamis
波や津波も発生します
In particular, our Yilan Plain is actually very flat, right?
特に宜蘭平原は実はとても平らなんですよね？
Waves of five meters may occur on the Yilan Plain
宜蘭平原では5メートルの波が発生する可能性があります
is the tsunami
津波です
Maybe the beach is the same
たぶんビーチも同じだろう
if ten meters
10メートルなら
There is no need for a third of Yilan to be soaked in water
宜蘭の3分の1を水に浸す必要はない
Well, of course we don't want this to happen.
もちろん、私たちはこのようなことが起こってほしくありません。
But what happens in nature is not whether we rest or not
しかし、自然界で起こることは、私たちが休むかどうかではありません。
that we have to be prepared
私たちは準備をしなければならないということ
Can't wait until we wish it didn't happen
そうならないことを願うまで待ちきれません
back to this volcanic disaster
この火山災害に戻ります
The world trends I just told you about are the scariest.
今話した世界の動向が一番怖いです。
That Long Yanliu is like this Xia Fuyi
ロング・ヤンリウはこんな感じ、シア・フイ
dragon smoke is hot but it's not scary
ドラゴンの煙は熱いけど怖くない
there's a little bit of what's actually it's slow
実際には遅い部分が少しあります
you see it you run probably past it
あなたはそれを見ます、あなたはおそらくそれを通り過ぎて走ります
Therefore, the disaster of Longyanliu is actually relatively limited.
したがって、龍岩流の災害は実際には比較的限定的である。
The other thing is that we mentioned the earthquake just now.
もう一つは、先ほど地震の話が出ました。
Let's talk about the volcanic glow and mudflow
火山の輝きと泥流について話しましょう
Special Volcano Hui we just talked about
先ほど話した特別な火山フイ
Don't talk about the flow of the world, dragons and smoke are all at close range
世界の流れを語るな 龍も煙もすぐ近くにある
it's only dangerous if you touch it
触っただけで危険です
But Volcano is not
しかし、火山はそうではありません
it can go far
それは遠くまで行ける
cause you a lot of trouble
あなたに多大なご迷惑をおかけします
This was also last month
これも先月のことです
Yindao volcano erupts again
銀島火山が再び噴火
Luer Island next to it is Yin Island
ルアー島の隣はイン島です
This is Lugoshima City
ここはルゴ島市です
The city of Luer Island has probably remained the same, with about 500,000 people.
ルアー島の都市はおそらく人口50万人程度と変わっていない。
small cities
小さな都市
this volcanic glow
この火山の輝き
The sound instructor is very active
音響インストラクターが大活躍
I'm going to the audio guide
音声ガイドに行きます
5 to 10 times
5～10回
i won't remember
覚えていないでしょう
about twice
2回くらい
There will be a volcanic glow once
一度火山の輝きがあります
I have a high memory
私は記憶力が高いです
I often go to see the volcanic glow
私はよく火山の輝きを見に行きます
It's coming up like a chimney
煙突のように上がってくる
What about the result?
結果はどうですか？
this lure tutor is like this
このルアー家庭教師はこんな感じです
This is either going to sea or volcanic glow
これは海か火山の輝きのどちらかになります
So Mr. Lure is very used to
だからルアーさんはとても慣れています
This Volcanic Fai follows them
このヴォルカニック・ファイは彼らを追いかけます
live together
一緒に住む
That
それか
Mount Aso two years ago
2年前の阿蘇山
Just the whole surrounding city
周囲の街全体だけ
The car is all covered
車はすべて覆われています
This of course just causes you
もちろん、これはあなたを引き起こすだけです
life is very inconvenient
生活はとても不便です
It will not cause your life and property
あなたの生命や財産に影響を与えることはありません
big threat
大きな脅威
That's a small volcanic eruption
小規模な火山の噴火です
But the volcano had a big eruption
しかしその火山は大噴火を起こした
eruptions smaller than
～より小さい噴火
Like this one in the 900 million year old Philippines
9億年前のフィリピンにあるこのようなもの
Pinglaotupu erupts here
ここでピンラオトゥプが噴火します
This is where Manila is located
ここがマニラの場所です
Usually Tupu is in
通常はトゥプが入っています
This volcano has actually been in the past ten or twenty years
この火山は実はここ10年か20年の間にできたものです。
Already a relatively large volcano
すでに比較的大きな火山です
what effect it has
どのような効果があるのか
because this volcano is very lucky
この火山はとても幸運だから
why lucky
なぜ幸運なのか
Because the United States has a so-called air base in the Philippines
米国はフィリピンにいわゆる空軍基地を持っているため
That's Clark Air Force Base.
それがクラーク空軍基地です。
They were two weeks before the eruption
噴火の2週間前だった
Because the USGS in the United States helped with the investigation
米国のUSGSが捜査に協力したため
Because of the problem with their F-16 fighter jets
F-16戦闘機の問題のため
So they found out they couldn't do it.
それで彼らはそれができないことに気づきました。
This volcano should erupt within ten days
この火山は10日以内に噴火するはずです
All the F-16s at Clark AFB have flown away
クラーク空軍基地のすべてのF-16が飛び去った
only this one left
これだけ残ってた
This is a broken plane
これは壊れた飛行機です
it can't run so keep it
実行できないのでそのままにしておきます
So a lot of volcanoes were built
それでたくさんの火山が作られました
This is a very successful
これは大成功です
Successful examples of volcano monitoring
火山監視の成功例
Of course, the United States and the Philippines
もちろんアメリカやフィリピンも
result of cooperation
協力の結果
then look at this
それからこれを見てください
Although this has these volcanic ash at close range
この火山灰が至近距離にあるのに
But this volcanic ash is not only
しかし、この火山灰はそれだけではありません
Will it affect the vicinity?
近隣への影響はありますか？
you see this is
これはわかりますか
this before the eruption
これは噴火前
tens of kilometers of this
ここから数十キロ
These ash
この灰は
june eruption
6月の噴火
all turn red
全部赤くなる
That volcanic ash drifts to
その火山灰が漂ってくるのは、
very very high peak go
非常に非常に高いピークを行く
then you see this is
そうすると、これがわかります
august to december
8月から12月まで
slowly recovered
ゆっくりと回復した
restore to original
元に戻す
So about half a year
それで半年くらい
The whole of this volcanic ash is in
この火山灰は全部入っています
high up on earth
地球の高いところに
With the wind
風とともに
Although this is
これではありますが、
Larger volcanoes this year
今年はさらに大きな火山が発生
But if you follow history
しかし歴史をたどってみると
It is the kind of big volcanic eruption in the historical era
有史以来の大噴火のようなものだ
can take the whole earth
地球全体を手に入れることができる
of
の
the whole atmosphere is covered
全体の雰囲気が覆われている
do not come in
入ってこないでください
creatures of the earth
地球の生き物たち
or
また
will even become extinct
絶滅することさえある
This is history
これは歴史です
That's what the historical evidence says
歴史的証拠がそう言っている
extinction of some creatures
一部の生物の絶滅
In fact, it may be related to the volcano
実は火山と関係があるのか​​もしれない
Large volcanic eruptions are closely related
大規模な火山噴火は密接に関係している
well that
まあそれは
In 2011 this Icelandic volcano
2011 年にこのアイスランドの火山
Maybe everyone has the impression
もしかしたら誰もがそんな印象を持っているかもしれません
So a volcano erupts
それで火山が噴火する
The entire volcano will float to the continent of Europe
火山全体がヨーロッパ大陸に浮かぶだろう
All flights across continental Europe are grounded
ヨーロッパ大陸のすべての便が運航停止
The whole traveler
旅行者全体
or the economy
あるいは経済
They assess a whole bunch of losses
彼らは大量の損失を評価します
Then this is a bigger volcano
そうすると、これはもっと大きな火山です
In fact, it's not just the effect of close range.
実は、これは近距離の影響だけではありません。
In fact, all human beings will be affected
実は人類全員が影響を受けることになる
Let's see how much it erupts
どれくらい噴火するか見てみましょう
That
それか
Probably the largest volcano is nothing more than this one
おそらく最大の火山はこの火山にほかなりません
this is america
ここはアメリカです
above the address they have three different colors
住所の上には 3 つの異なる色があります
That's 2.2 million years
それは220万年です
1.32 million years
132万年
640,000 years
64万年
Area covered by three eruptions of different ages
年代の異なる 3 つの噴火が起こった地域
Geologist doing occupational survey
職業調査を行う地質学者
outlined
概説した
So there's a super nutrition store under Yellowstone Park
イエローストーン公園の下にスーパー栄養店があります
This also has a movie in production
こちらは映画も制作中です
It's also very sensational
それもとてもセンセーショナルです
or very scary
またはとても怖い
So the United States is actually very important to this Yellowstone Park.
つまり、米国はこのイエローストーン公園にとって実は非常に重要な存在なのです。
is very, very serious to treat
治療は非常に深刻です
Why
なぜ
Of course you divide 2.2 by 13
もちろん、2.2を13で割ります。
About once every 700,000 years
約70万年に1回
So last time it was 640,000
前回は64万でした
seems to be coming soon
もうすぐ来るようです
If round by cycle
サイクルごとにラウンドする場合
If it is true, it represents their age
それが本当なら、それは彼らの年齢を表す
Seems like it's about to erupt
噴火しそうな気がする
This is the result of a supervolcano
これは超火山の結果です
Volcanic ash certainly has a big impact
もちろん火山灰の影響も大きい
Let's go back to this lahar
この泥流に戻りましょう
That's the lahar flow in Colombia, Central America.
それが中米コロンビアの泥流です。
What is a volcanic mudflow? We have it in Taiwan
火山泥流とは何ですか? 台湾にはそれがあります
Everyone knows this landslide
この土砂崩れは誰もが知っています
It's just water, mud, or he just flows down
それはただの水か泥か、あるいはただ流れ落ちるだけだ
It's even scarier at the volcano
火山だともっと怖い
volcanic ash is lighter
火山灰は軽い
so it is easier to flow
だから流れやすくなる
And the ash is very thick in the volcanic area
そして、火山地帯では灰が非常に厚いです
So all at once the whole mudslide comes over
それで一気に土砂崩れが起こる
that's especially this
それは特にこれです
This is in the mountains of Central America
ここは中米の山奥です
Usually like Yushan
普段は玉山みたいな
or higher these mountains
あるいはそれ以上の山々
it is covered with snow
それは雪で覆われています
But once the volcano came up,
しかし、ひとたび火山が隆起すると、
Is a high temperature with ice, snow, dragon
氷、雪、ドラゴンのある高温です
When you touch some of that snow, it will melt
その雪に触れると溶けてしまいます
produce a lot of water
水をたくさん生産する
Then the water brings down the ash
それから水が灰を降ろします
The whole shock
ショック全体
There are tens of thousands of people
何万人もいる
This is because it was far away from us in China and the United States.
中国やアメリカでは遠かったからです。
But in fact, the transmission of information
しかし、実際に情報を発信するということは、
if you look carefully
よく見ると
this is
これは
There will be such a big disaster in five or ten years
5年後か10年後にはあんな大きな災害が起きるだろう
will run out
足りなくなります
that mud flow is like this
泥の流れはこんな感じ
the whole of this
これ全体
Landslides in the South before Typhoon August 8
台風8号の前に南部で土砂崩れが発生
In fact, after the main disaster of these rivers
実際、これらの川の主要な災害の後、
Then the water goes into the village
それから水は村に流れ込みます
flooding
洪水
This is the moment when the volcano erupts
火山が噴火する瞬間です
Just so we said volcanic ash lahars
火山灰泥流と言ったとおりです
volcanic ash
火山灰溶溶溶
Water leaks, this is an instant disaster
水漏れ、これは一大事
But this mudslide
しかし、今回の土砂崩れ
this is endless
これは終わりがない
Why
なぜ
just a typhoon
ただの台風
water comes
水が来る
just bring a mudslide
土砂崩れをもたらすだけ
especially the philippines
特にフィリピン
Philippines at every turn
あらゆる場面でフィリピン
as long as a typhoon comes
台風が来る限り
Of course we are in Taiwan
もちろん台湾にいますよ
are often threatened by typhoons
しばしば台風の脅威にさらされる
But like the brand is the one next to me
でもブランドが私の隣にあるように
that is
あれは
The volcanic ash is carried all the time
火山灰は常に運ばれている
the river
川
Then the whole flood was changed to a lot of villages
その後、洪水全体が多くの村に変わりました
that may be thirty years
それは30年になるかもしれない
That volcano will not be taken away
あの火山は奪われない
Then keep repeating these
その後、これらを繰り返し続けます
menacing thing
脅迫的なもの
well that
まあそれは
Give a general introduction to Vesvi and Pompeii or volcanoes
ヴェスヴィとポンペイ、または火山についての一般的な紹介をする
We will go directly back to our Taipei and Mainland China
私たちは台北と中国本土に直接戻ります
Of course this is imaginary
もちろんこれは想像です
This is our 101 Dalun Volcano in Taipei Basin
これは台北盆地にある第 101 ダルン火山です
What if the Great Looming erupted?
もし大迫り来る大爆発が起きたらどうなるでしょうか？
These dragonfly flows, crater flows, or lahars
これらのトンボ流、クレーター流、泥流
Anyway, Xianjian Huohuo may all go to the Taipei Basin
とにかく、Xianjian Huohhuはすべて台北盆地に行くかもしれません
Then if these dragon flies block the entrance of Guandu
もしこのトンボが関渡の入り口を塞いだら
Danshui and Keelung can't get out
淡水と基隆は出られない
Will there be this legendary Kangxi Taipei Lake?
この伝説の康渓台北湖は存在するのでしょうか？
won't run out
なくなりません
So as long as it happens there is a possibility
だからそれが起こる限り可能性はある
The distance is actually
その距離は実際には
I really hope to connect 101 with Qixing Mountain
101と七星山を結びたいと心から願っています
In fact, we think the most likely to live
実際、私たちが最も生存する可能性が高いと考えているのは、
active area
アクティブエリア
Well, it's actually less than 15 kilometers
まあ、実際には15キロ未満です
is a very very short distance
とてもとても短い距離です
Very short straight line distance
直線距離非常短
You can imagine the volcano bit coming up
火山のビットが近づいていることを想像できるでしょう
The whole of Taipei probably
おそらく台北全体
with the guide for
そのガイドを使って
The city next to it has almost the same impact
隣の都市もほぼ同じ影響
Then we also do a little bit of simulation
次に、少しシミュレーションも行います
This is assuming that there is a volcanic eruption in Qixing Mountain
七星山の火山噴火があった場合を想定しています。
What will happen to Longweiliu
ロンウェイリウはどうなるのか
This is the simulated location
ここがシミュレーションの場所です
Then you give me a little closer look
それから、もう少し詳しく見てください
The different colors are its thickness
色の違いは厚みです
or its area of influence
またはその影響範囲
Then don't look carefully at this
じゃあ、これを注意深く見ないでください
because you'll see
あなたは見るでしょうから
where is my home
私の家はどこですか
then i will
それなら私がします
In fact, I have always
実際、私はいつも
I made it about four or five years ago
4、5年くらい前に作りました
I have never dared to show off
あえて見せびらかしたことがない
Until recently because volcanoes in the sea have been
最近まで海の中に火山があったため、
Is it legislation?
法律ですか？
When the government is going to face
政府が直面するとき
so
それで
This is for reference only
これは参考用です
that's for
それはのためです
If it's Mount Suzui, it's underground, it's Jinshan
鈴井山なら地下、金山なら
Just to the north, we know that Jinshan is very productive.
すぐ北にある金山は生産性が高いことがわかっています。
In fact, many people are very concerned
実はとても心配している人も多いのです
Will it have an impact on very productive
生産性への影響はありますか
I don't comment on this
これについてはコメントしません
just do a little mock work
ちょっとした模擬作業をするだけです
that of course affects the range
それは当然範囲に影響します
It all depends on the amount it erupts, right?
すべては噴火の量次第ですよね？
It erupts a little bit, of course it has a very small area of effect
少し噴火します、もちろん影響は狭い範囲にあります
If the amount of eruption is large
噴火量が多い場合
It certainly has a large reach
確かにリーチは広いですね
that eruption is small
その噴火は小さいです
now we don't know
今は分かりません
but i'll tell you later
でも後で言います
if it
それであれば
erupting next month
来月噴火する
I have a very high chance
非常に高い確率で
will tell everyone
みんなに言うだろう
Will the eruption be big or small
噴火は大きいか小さいか
This is an opinion with some scientific estimates
これはいくつかの科学的推定を伴う意見です
well, this volcanic ash
さて、この火山灰
It is also what people often talk about
それは人々がよく話していることでもあります
This is the public health teacher of CUHK
こちらはCUHKの保健の先生です
help with some simulations
いくつかのシミュレーションを手伝ってください
In fact, he did it 365 days a year
実際、彼はそれを1年365日やっていた
According to different seasons, different directions
さまざまな季節、さまざまな方向に応じて
when the volcano comes up
火山が起きるとき
how should it float
どうやって浮かせるか
Then of course we have 365 days of data
もちろん、365 日分のデータもあります
we are all running
私たちは皆走っています
I'm here only spring and autumn
私がここにいるのは春と秋だけ
Of course spring, summer, autumn and winter are different
もちろん春、夏、秋、冬は違います
Every day actually has something to do with the direction of the wind
毎日は実は風向きと関係があるのです
That was six years ago
それは6年前のことでした
When our TVO was established
TVO設立当時
we just want to say
私たちはただ言いたいだけです
If the volcano erupts that day
もしあの日火山が噴火したら
How should volcanic ash spread?
火山灰はどのように拡散すればよいのでしょうか？
Just go to Japan to this
これをするために日本に行くだけです
Spread in this direction of Hainan Island
海南島のこの方向に広がる
This is an impression
これは感想です
Just tell these phenomena
これらの現象をただ伝えてください
Okay, we talked for a long time
さて、長い間話しました
Actually that's what I've been saying
実はそれは私が言っていたことなんです
if if if the volcano erupts
もし火山が噴火したら
if a volcano erupts
火山が噴火したら
but the real problem is
しかし本当の問題は
Will continental volcanoes erupt?
大陸の火山は噴火するのでしょうか？
then this is back to us
それからこれは私たちに戻ってきます
serious scientific question
重大な科学的疑問
And we have been for about ten years
そして、私たちは約10年間そうでした
A group of people trying to find the answer
答えを見つけようとする人々のグループ
before finding the answer
答えを見つける前に
when i was a student
私が学生だったとき
words read by people in ninth science
第 9 科学の人々が読む言葉
So I can know that this is our terrain group in Taipei
これで、これが台北の地形グループであることがわかります
The red area is the fire dust rock
赤い部分が火粉岩です
Huochen rock is the dragon rock that represents the eruption of the volcano on the surface.
火晨石は火山の噴火を地表に表現した龍石です。
igneous rock body
火山岩
So this is probably like this
ということで、おそらくこんな感じです
Because in Taiwan we don't have
台湾には無いから
There is no record of volcanic eruptions in history
歴史上、火山噴火の記録はない
So most people want to say a volcanic eruption
だからほとんどの人は火山の噴火だと言いたがる
Taiwan dare not do our things
台湾は我々のことをあえてしない
Taipei will never
台北は決してないだろう
But according to geologists to do some dating of these red stones in this area
しかし、地質学者によると、この地域の赤い石の年代測定を行う予定です。
The so-called dating is to find out the age of its eruption
いわゆる年代測定とは、噴火の年代を調べることです。
Was it 10,000 years ago, 100,000 years ago, or 1,000,000 years ago?
それは1万年前でしたか、10万年前でしたか、それとも100万年前でしたか？
They can do it based on that parity year
その平価年に基づいてそれを行うことができます
Do the comparison and get the result
比較を行って結果を得る
This is an old picture from the 1980s
これは1980年代の古い写真です
That could have had a little eruption about a million years ago
約100万年前に小規模な噴火があった可能性がある
At the time of 800,000 years, the
80万年の時点では、
Volcanoes began to emerge from Dalin Volcano
大林火山から火山が出現し始めた
then four hundred thousand years more
それからさらに40万年
Then came this hundred thousand years
それからこの十万年が来た
I feel like it stopped
止まったような気がする
Therefore, because the data are provided for 100,000 years
したがって、データは10万年分提供されるため、
There is no data for 0.1 million years
10万年分のデータがない
So there is no eruption in history
つまり歴史上噴火は存在しない
This address home tells us that 100,000 years
この住所は、10万年を物語っています。
seems to be gone
いなくなってしまったようだ
So for a long, long time in the past
だから、ずっと昔から、
It's been a long time, everyone, the mainland is very common
皆さんお久しぶりです、本土はよくあることです
Continental Volcanoes or Yangmingshan National Park
大陸火山または陽明山国立公園
just to play
ただ遊ぶためだけに
it's not threatening to us
それは私たちにとって脅威ではありません
But about ten years of work
でも、10年くらいの仕事で
If we go to mainland volcanoes to see
本土の火山を見に行ったら
This is a surface fumarole hot spring, right?
ここは地表噴気温泉ですよね？
This is a typical volcanic area
ここは典型的な火山地帯です
Especially this geochemical analysis
特にこの地球化学分析
This is the work done by professors from Taiwan and Taiwan.
これは日台の先生方の研究です。
He is still equal to the pioneer
彼は依然として先駆者に匹敵する
He did some of these chemical analyzes of the fumaroles
彼は噴気孔の化学分析のいくつかを行いました
just tell us
教えてください
That thing is not a feature of the surface
それは表面の特徴ではありません
but what
でも何
If the earth is not deep, the earth is slow
地球が深くなければ地球は遅い
That's Teacher Yang Cannan
それはヤン・カンナン先生です
Di Xiaohua learns from the perspective of the flower, it looks like it is alive
ディ・シャオファは花の視点から学びました、それは生きているように見えます
But no one does physics
でも誰も物理学やってないよ
so he advised me to do it
それで彼は私にそうするようアドバイスした
At that time, I just came back from a year-long visit to Japan
その時、私は1年間の日本旅行から帰ってきたばかりでした。
Saw a lot of volcanoes in Japan
日本でたくさんの火山を見ました
I just jump in and do it
私はただ飛び込んでそれをするだけです
Then I jumped in and now I can't come back
それから私は飛び込んだ、そして今は戻って来ることができない
more and more miracles
ますます奇跡が起こる
Then anyway, I will cast the Earthquake King
それならともかく、地震王をキャストします
so i watched a lot
だからたくさん見ました
There are many, many earthquakes in Dalian Mountain
大連山では地震が多い
Then in these earthquakes
それから、今回の地震では
What particularly attracts me is
私が特に惹かれるのは、
There are quite a few volcanic earthquakes to see
かなりの数の火山性地震が見られます
The traditional ones are general fault earthquakes and volcanic earthquakes
従来のものは、断層地震と火山性地震です。
Its shape and its physical properties are completely different
形状も物性も全く異なります
He has someone to introduce a few
彼には何人か紹介してくれる人がいる
Then, like this air-made radar, you can see the crater burst
すると、この航空レーダーのように、クレーターの破裂が見えます。
it's all new
それはすべて新しいです
the rep said it wasn't weathered
担当者は風化していないと言った
didn't get overshadowed by the 10th
10日までに影が薄れなかった
mean it's new
新しいという意味
Then the level car two is Japan one
じゃあレベル２の車は日本の１です
A queen uncle of mine used to sit with me
私の叔父の女王がよく私と一緒に座っていました
There may be rises and falls
上がることもあれば下がることもあるかもしれない
It means he seems to be moving
彼は動いているようだという意味
rather than stable
安定というより
Then this date is special
それならこの日付は特別です
last most important
最後一項最重要
this was before
これは前にあった
Deputy Director Chen Zonghua
副所長陳宗華
He took him to Russia
彼は彼をロシアに連れて行った
found a german
ドイツ人を見つけた
I found it because Russia is also full of volcanoes.
ロシアにも火山がたくさんあるので見つけました。
Then comes the year of the Volcano Society
そして火山協会の年がやって来ます
Because we don't have the
なぜなら、私たちはそれを持っていないからです。
very good expert
とても良い専門家
So I invite these foreign scholars to help
そこで私はこれらの外国人学者に協力を呼びかけます。
he decided probably
彼はおそらく決めた
five thousand to six thousand years
5千年から6千年
Anyway, he made a mistake.
とにかく、彼は間違いを犯した。
But whether it's five thousand or six thousand
でもそれが5000だろうが6000だろうが
This means a lot
これには大きな意味があります
What does that mean
どういう意味ですか
In the Republic of China
中華民国では
In 1999
1999年
We will hold a meeting of experts and scholars at the Geological Survey Institute
地質調査所で専門家・学者による会議を開催します
Then we put Chancellor Volcano
次に、Chancellor Volcanoを配置します
discussed for a long time
長い間議論された
Although there are very
とてもたくさんありますが、
strong dispute
激しい論争
Some people say Yes and No
イエスともノーとも言う人もいる
Some people say that ordinary volcanoes
普通の火山だと言う人もいます。
Volcanoes are all over the world
火山は世界中にあります
extinct or active volcano
死火山または活火山
Natalon Volcano
ナタロン火山
The result of our final discussion is that
私たちの最終的な議論の結果は、
dormant volcano
休火山
What is a dormant volcano
休火山とは
it is a volcano
それは火山です
but it's sleeping now
でも今は寝ています
It may not wake up one day
いつか目覚めなくなるかもしれない
Then this living Huohuo Songshan
それからこの生きているフオフオ・ソンシャン
What is the name of the volcano?
火山の名前は何ですか?
Like Xia Haoyi
シア・ハオイのように
You can go to see that magma anytime
そのマグマにいつでも会いに行けるよ
Or go to Aso Volcano
あるいは阿蘇火山に行くか
it's smoking
煙っている
boot smoke
ブーツの煙
This is a living volcano
これは生きた火山です
So the Great Looming is
それで、大いなる迫り来るのは、
is alive
生きている
It looks like there is no activity
活動はないようです
Then with this result
するとこの結果で
So this is the definition of volcanology
これが火山学の定義です
that is
あれは
Active in ten thousand years
1万年も活動する
you have this record
あなたはこの記録を持っています
I classify it as a volcano
私はそれを火山に分類します
just have a bad record
ただ悪い成績を残しているだけ
special tube
特殊なチューブ
pay attention to it
それに注意してください
This is the experience above
以上が体験談です
But the phenomenon is
しかし、その現象は、
I personally feel the phenomenon
私もその現象を個人的に感じています
It doesn't have to be more scientifically meaningful.
それは科学的に意味のあるものである必要はありません。
That is, if you can confirm that there is a magma chamber
つまりマグマだまりがあることが確認できれば
like this yellowstone scientist said
このイエローストーンの科学者が言ったように
There is a big magma chamber underneath
その下には大きなマグマだまりがある
of course it's alive
もちろん生きています
If Yellowstone Park just talked about
イエローストーンパークについて話していたら
The last major eruption was 640,000 years ago
最後の大噴火は64万年前
This is very big, 10,000 years, that should be
これは非常に大きい、10,000年であるはずです
10 volcanic
10火山的
But Yellowstone can't use rules of thumb
しかしイエローストーンは経験則を使えない
law of phenomena
現象の法則
It's the magma chamber that you found
あなたが見つけたマグマだまりです
live without meaning
意味もなく生きる
This is a general definition of something like
これは次のようなものの一般的な定義です
After that with the process
それからプロセス後
In fact, for the past five or six years
実はここ5、6年、
every time because i do adult volcano
大人の火山やってるから毎回
Tell the Ministry of Science and Technology that this is a volcano
科学技術省にこれは火山だと伝えてください
Looks like I'm a volcano
まるで火山のようだ
At that time, the natural Sisi of the Ministry of Science and Technology
その時、科学技術省の天然シシィ
Chen Yigao
チェン・イーガオ
He is also the 17th of National Taiwan University
彼は国立台湾大学の17代目でもあります。
we are still mature
私たちはまだ成熟しています
every time i meet you i say
あなたに会うたびに私は言います
Lin Zheng, where are the volcanic magma chambers?
林鄭さん、火山のマグマだまりはどこにありますか？
When you meet me, ask me where the magma chamber is
会ったらマグマだまりがどこにあるのか聞いてください
I was asked by him for five or six years
5、6年前から彼に頼まれていました
then i always wanted to talk
それから私はいつも話したいと思っていました
In fact, I probably have a spectrum how to do it
実際、私はおそらくそれを行う方法のスペクトルを持っています
but no evidence
しかし証拠がない
Then I thought
それから私は思いました
think of a very simple concept
非常に単純な概念を考えてください
Just use the shadow of the magma chamber
マグマだまりの影を利用するだけ
The concept of this shadow is very simple
この影のコンセプトは非常にシンプルです
we see the shadow of this plane
この飛行機の影が見えます
We don't need to look up to know
知るために調べる必要はない
There was a plane in the sky
空に飛行機がありました
Because the sun hits the plane
飛行機に太陽が当たるから
If you can't penetrate it, there is a shadow on the surface
貫通できない場合は表面に影ができます
it's clear
それは明らかだ
The X-ray on the medical
医療上のX線
Everyone, this X-ray hits the bone
皆さん、このレントゲンは骨に当たります
Different from tissue because of fine absorption
組織とは異なり、微細な吸収により
So if the finger breaks off
それで指が折れたら
see the crack
亀裂を見る
So this is because of the X-ray test
レントゲン検査のせいですね
difference between tissue and bone
組織と骨の違い
Come on, earth science actually started more than 100 years ago
地球科学は実際には 100 年以上前に始まりました
There is such a concept that
そういう概念があるのですが、
when the earthquake happened
地震が起こったとき
Earth science has long known that
地球科学は長い間それを知っていました
This external cooperation is
この外部協力は、
out of code it is a liquid
コードから外れた場合、それは液体です
This is 2900 kilometers from the surface to the outside
ここは地表から外まで2900キロメートル
is a very, very deep distance
とてもとても深い距離です
But why do scientists know it's a liquid
しかし、なぜ科学者はそれが液体であることを知っているのでしょうか
It is based on the shadow of the S wave
S波の影をベースにしています
Seismic waves hit the red part
赤い部分に地震波が当たる
you can see in this section
このセクションで見ることができます
There is this S wave signal
このS波信号があります
but you have this one on the back
でもこれはあなたが背中に持っているものです
brown side
茶色の面
You can't find a straight S wave
まっすぐなS波は見つからない
because of what
何かのせいで
S wave blocked by Out of Code
S 波はコード外によりブロックされました
It's just a liquid substance, it can't go through it.
それは単なる液体の物質なので、通過することはできません。
S waves can't penetrate
S波は通らない
then this maybe
それならこれは多分
To put it simply, let me tell you
簡単に言っておきますが、
This is the P wave
これがP波です
when there is an earthquake
地震が起きたとき
Anyway, elastic waves will produce P and S
とにかく弾性波はPとSを生み出す
This is a heavy or compression wave
これは重波または圧縮波です
it's a bump
それはでこぼこです
Look at this black
この黒さを見てください
it shrinks and then stretches
それは縮んでから伸びます
It's like hitting a pool ball
ビリヤードのボールを打つようなものだ
So the energy is transferred in one
つまり、エネルギーは一度に伝達されます
What is the S wave
S波とは何ですか
S wave is like dead
S波は死んだようなものだ
it's twisted it's clipped
ねじれている、切り取られている
So one is a linear motion
つまり、1 つは直線運動です
one is twisting sideways
片方は横にねじれている
This is of course simpler, for the sake of simplicity
もちろん、わかりやすくするために、これはより単純です
That is to say, if the left side is a solid
つまり、左側が固体の場合、
on the right is a liquid
右側は液体です
What is the difference between solid and liquid
固体と液体の違いは何ですか
The solid is the gap between each molecule and the powder oil molecule
固体は各分子と粉末油の分子の間の隙間です
Well caught by this chemical piece
この化学物質によく引っかかりました
it can't run around
走り回ることはできない
Meaning you're on my left is on the left
つまり、あなたは私の左側にいるということは、左側にいるということです
you can't run to the right
右に走ってはいけない
But the liquid, the liquid, you can run as you please
でも液体、液体、好きに走っていいよ
is liquid or gas
液体か気体か
It means that it doesn't have these sugar yellows, so it is gradually grasping
これらの砂糖の黄味がないということなので、徐々に把握されてきています
So what do these two different behaviors cause?
これら 2 つの異なる動作は何を引き起こすのでしょうか?
P4 If you turn around from this side by external force
P4 外力により手前から曲がると
it will
そうなる
it will hit this
これに当たるだろう
then this hits this
それからこれはこれに当たります
this hit this
これはこれに当たりました
So P4 will transfer energy
つまり、P4はエネルギーを伝達します
Then you when this one comes running
それから、これが走ってきたとき、あなたは
This S wave because it has sugar yellow
シュガーイエローがあるからこのS波
it will pull over
それは引っ張るだろう
its sugar yellow will elongate
その砂糖の黄色は伸びるだろう
so this will bring
これにより、
then take one by one
それから一つずつ取ってください
So the S wave will pass like this
S波はこうやって通過していきます
So when solid
それで、固まったら
Both P and S pass
PもSも合格
but when the liquid
しかし、液体のとき
P wave is a transfer, S wave because the two have no relationship
P 波は送信、S 波は両者に関係がないため
So this hole will not move
だからこの穴は動かない
To give a very simple ratio, everyone sitting here
非常に単純な比率で言えば、ここに座っている全員が
If we hold hands, we are solid
手を繋いだら 僕らはしっかりする
when one of them leans back
そのうちの1人が後ろにもたれると
The one next to it will also pull on it
隣の人も引っ張ります
so it will pull one by one
それで一つずつ引っ張っていきます
So this is the characteristic of S wave
これがS波の特徴です
If we don't hold hands, it will be liquid
手を繋がないと液体になってしまう
one of them lay forward
そのうちの1人は前に横たわっていました
Lean forward, the one next to it will not be disturbed
前かがみになると、隣の人は邪魔されません
is a property of solid liquids
固体液体の性質です
According to this, we can test that
これによると、それをテストできます
What kind of liquid or solid exists in the earth
地球にはどんな液体や固体が存在するのか
just
ただ
Well, what we imagine is that
さて、私たちが想像しているのは、
Except for out of core, the earth is liquid outside
地球は核の外を除いて外側は液体です
Neihe , not this magma chamber
内河、このマグマだまりではありません
It should be that the magma with high temperature is liquid
高温のマグマは液体であるはずです
So I was thinking that S wave will definitely disappear after hitting this point.
なので、ここまで来るとS波は確実に消えるだろうと思っていました。
right
右
Alright, then I set up a lot of earthquake chairs here in Yangmingshan.
よし、それではここ陽明山に地震椅子をたくさん設置する。
Then take advantage of the very deep bottom
次に、非常に深い底を利用します
We have many large and deep earthquakes off the coast of Yilan
宜蘭沖では大規模で深い地震が何度も発生しています。
and then straight up from the bottom
そして下からまっすぐ上に
then hit our area
それから私たちの地域に行きます
Then I went to check which one had S wave and which one didn't.
次に、どれがS波を持っているか、どれがS波を持っていないかを確認しました。
You can see these earthquake stations in blue
これらの地震観測点は青色で表示されます
It can all see S waves
S波が全部見える
The only areas that are red
赤い部分だけ
it can't see s waves
波が見えない
Of course, P wave and S wave look like everyone
もちろんP波もS波もみんな似てるよ
is a bit professional
少し専門的です
but it's not that hard
でもそれはそれほど難しいことではありません
I put the record of red and blue on the next one
赤と青の記録を次に載せます
The following is the arrival of the P wave
以下はP波の到来です
Then the S wave arrives and it's very clear
そしてS波が来てとてもクリアです
But when the seismic waves hit this magma chamber
しかし、地震波がこのマグマだまりにぶつかると、
The P wave can pass through to the S wave and cannot be found at all.
P波はS波まで突き抜けてしまい全く見つかりません。
It just disappears, disappears, and there is a shadow
ただ消えて消えて影がある
So this four-one picture means
つまり、この 4 つ 1 つの絵が意味するのは、
When hitting the magma chamber, the S wave disappeared
マグマだまりにぶつかるとS波が消えた
S wave will run out when you miss it
S波は逃すとなくなる
So according to this it is simple
したがって、これによれば、それは簡単です
Let's just draw a cartoon
ちょっと漫画を描いてみよう
The magma chamber is here, if you hit this
ここに当たればマグマだまりはここだ
You can't see the yellow side
黄色い面は見えません
was blocked
ブロックされました
if this is true
これが本当なら
We also double-check that
私たちもそれを再確認します
If the magma chamber is here
ここにマグマだまりがあるなら
S waves can't pass through, but P waves
S波は通らないがP波は通る
What about heavy waves, heavy waves, solid liquids, its fine
重い波、重い波、固体液体はどうですか、大丈夫です
it can penetrate
それは浸透することができます
although it can penetrate
浸透できるのに
but it gets slower
しかしそれは遅くなります
because it is liquid
液体なので
so it goes slower
だから遅くなる
So I'll walk here together as sidekicks
だから相棒としてここを一緒に歩いて行こう
these two it only goes here
この2つはここにしかありません
This is the four one picture
これはフォーワンの写真です
But it's clear
でもそれは明らかです
Let's see the earthquake hit here
ここで地震が起きたところを見てみましょう
We got a signal on the surface
地上で信号を受信しました
Then this is simulated
次に、これをシミュレートします
If you hit the magma chamber here it will slow down
ここのマグマだまりに当たると速度が落ちる
Then the S wave disappeared
そしてS波は消えた
On the right hand side is our observation
右側は私たちの観察です
The distance that will be written every time a wave hits the magma chamber
波がマグマだまりにぶつかるたびに刻まれる距離
in this dark place
この暗い場所で
will appear here to arrive
ここに現れて到着します
But as soon as you hit the magma door
でもマグマドアにぶつかるとすぐに
it won't be here
ここにはないだろう
it's a little slow
少し遅いです
So you look at the S wave and don't see it
だからあなたはS波を見てもそれが見えない
Then the P wave is tired again
それからP波はまた疲れます
for me
私のため
this is no doubt space
ここは間違いなく宇宙です
There is a liquid substance under the ground
地下には液体の物質がある
The liquid substance has said
液体物質はこう言った
Not necessarily magma or water
マグマや水とは限りません
That's impossible
それ無理
Why
なぜ
At 20 kilometers the water will be squeezed out
20キロで水が絞り出される
magma
マグマ
Its density is closer to that of stone
密度が石に近い
it can be kept
保管できます
so it can't be water
だから水ではありえない
Of course magma is the best and only explanation
もちろんマグマが最良かつ唯一の説明です
Then its size is about
それからそのサイズは約です
GOO!
グー！
70 square kilometers
70平方キロメートル
How big is 70 square kilometers
70平方キロメートルってどのくらいの大きさですか
is its area
そのエリアです
About a quarter of the size of the administrative district of Taipei City
台北市の行政区の約4分の1の広さ
Let's all do something
みんなで何かやりましょう
A little bigger than Siling District
シリン区より少し大きい
It is slightly smaller than Xinyi Songshan Nangang in the East District
東区の信義松山南港より少し小さいくらいです。
what's the point of this
これはどういう意味ですか
As long as a region of a local kilometer
ローカルキロメートルの範囲に限り
so come on lava
だから溶岩に来てください
probably just like
おそらく同じように
The pavement is so big before reaching Pinya
ピニャに着くまでの歩道はとても広いです
possible to st seabee st helens
セントシービーセントヘレンズに可能
erupt a little bigger
もう少し大きく噴火する
that would be terrible
それはひどいことになるだろう
so instead of saying
だから言う代わりに
All this magma goes to the surface
このマグマはすべて地表に出ます
Actually it's only 1%
実はそれはたったの1%なんです
a percentage to the surface
表面に対するパーセンテージ
In fact, the volcano will erupt
実は火山が噴火するんです
It's dangerous and powerful
それは危険で強力です
Well, of course this is
まあ、もちろんこれは
Because of the results of these studies
こういった研究結果のおかげで
So the central
それで中央は
except the legislature
立法府を除いて
Then the Executive Yuan
それから行政院
have done some coping with this
これにある程度の対処をしました
So elegant planning for volcanic disasters
火山災害に対する非常にエレガントな計画
no matter central place now
今は中心部に関係なく
must follow above
上記に従う必要があります
Some mechanisms of this strain
この菌株のいくつかのメカニズム
good though
いいけど
find the magma chamber
マグマだまりを見つける
but for me
でも私にとっては
In fact, the challenge is greater
実際には、課題はさらに大きくなります
The reason is that this is
その理由は、これは、
What we call Huang Xinhua
私たちが黄新華と呼んでいるもの
this colleague did
この同僚はやった
at this
この時点で
Made by Huang's Park
ファンズ・パーク製
There's a magma chamber under it
その下にはマグマだまりがある
there is a
ある
that's in taiwan
それは台湾にあります
I think it's 20 kilometers
20キロくらいあると思います
what we see is this
私たちが見ているのはこれです
In fact, I am more worried about whether there is a potential
むしろ、その可能性があるかどうかの方が心配です。
Because our resolution is limited
私たちの解像度には限界があるので
so I dare not speak
だからあえて話さない
Does the upper crust have
上部の地殻にはありますか
So the Ministry of Science and Technology gave me an order to continue looking for
そこで科学技術省は私に、引き続き探し続けるよう命令を出しました。
Let's come up with a big plan
大きな計画を立てましょう
At the ninth month they are
9か月目では、
We are in the secret spicy earthquake war in northern Taiwan
私たちは台湾北部で密かに激しい地震戦争に参加しています
I hope that Minister Hill and Guishan Island
ヒル大臣と亀山島が無事であることを願っています。
Find it in the magma chambers of these two volcanoes
これら 2 つの火山のマグマだまりで見つけてください。
In fact, we also found the magma chamber on Guishan Island.
実際、亀山島でもマグマだまりが発見されました。
The article is under review
記事は審査中です
should be out soon
すぐに出るべきです
So there is definitely a magma reservoir under Guishan
つまり亀山の地下にはマグマだまりがあるのは間違いない
So we want to take this size depth
したがって、このサイズの奥行きをとりたいのです
Hope to find it out
それが見つかることを願っています
So I hope to finish this project in four years
だからこのプロジェクトは4年以内に終わらせたいと思っています
This is the black street station of our first year department
ここは私たちの学科1年生の黒街駅です
Then the next year I hope to fill the white
そして来年は白を埋めたいと思っています
Then the third year and the fourth year
それから3年目、4年目と
I can actually do some analysis and research
実際に分析や調査を行うことができます
good
良い
Next is this TVO
次はこちらのTVOです
this volcano
この火山
looks alive
生きているように見える
eruption cannot be ruled out
噴火の可能性も否定できない
what shall we do
何をしましょうか
This fear is often rooted in ignorance
この恐怖は無知に根ざしていることが多い
This is the Aso volcano just mentioned in Japan
これが先ほど日本で言及した阿蘇火山です
There are railroad houses and a lot of residents inside.
鉄道の家があり、中には多くの住民が住んでいます。
This is a big crater
ここは大きなクレーターです
people live in it
人々はそこに住んでいます
Lived for decades or hundreds of years, maybe a thousand years
何十年、何百年、もしかしたら千年も生きた
they didn't panic
彼らはパニックにならなかった
live inside the crater
クレーターの中に住んでいる
where is the reason
理由はどこにありますか
This one is more interesting
こっちの方が面白いよ
This is the eruption of Xiahao clam on May 1st
これは5月1日の夏豪貝の噴火です。
Director Chen of the NCD
あのNCD、あのチェン監督
just send me this one and say wow this one
これを送って、これはすごいと言ってください
super nice look
とても素敵な外観
This old beauty seems very handsome
この老いた美しさはとてもハンサムに見える
The volcano is covered in ashes
火山は灰に覆われている
He also raised his voice over there
あそこでも声を荒げた
The reason is that they are not afraid
理由は怖くないからです
The reason not to be afraid is not because you have courage
怖くないのは勇気があるからではない
because of something
何かのせいで
with this backing
この支援者と一緒に
This is the station of Xiahaoli Volcano Pass
ここが夏栗火山峠の駅です
Bottom this next to this
これの隣に
less than 100 meters
100メートル未満
When I visited last year, I asked him
去年訪れたときに聞いてみた
How deep is your crater along the river?
川沿いのクレーターの深さはどれくらいですか?
He said three kilometers
彼は3キロと言った
I said three kilometers, how dare you live here
私は3キロと言った、どうしてここに住むことができるの？
This has a history of 100 years
これには100年の歴史があります
Why
なぜ
Volcanic eruption will not be instant
火山の噴火はすぐには起こらない
There will be actions and warnings
アクションと警告が表示されます
So they can have a good grasp
彼らはよく理解できるようになります
so they pass
それで彼らは通ります
Earth science regardless of the air
空気を問わない地球科学
All kinds of monitoring on the surface or underground
地上または地下でのあらゆる種類の監視
as long as there is movement
動きがある限り
we can
我々はできる
before the volcano erupts
火山が噴火する前に
there should be
あるはずだ
just like Visway's
ヴィスウェイみたいに
This is the oldest
これが一番古いです
This one existed in 1841
これは 1841 年に存在しました
This is a very old painting
これはとても古い絵です
that is the status quo
それが現状です
this
これ
Isn't Pompeii already destroyed?
ポンペイってもう破壊されてるんじゃないの？
Why is there still a volcanic view on the station?
なぜ駅には火山の景色が残っているのでしょうか?
someone is
誰かが
sorry
ごめん
pompeii in
ポンペイで
South of Wesway
ビスウェイの南
To the north of him is Napolis
彼の北にはナポリスがある
So this also needs to be Watched
したがって、これも監視する必要があります
to observe
観察すること
another day
別の日
this volcano will
この火山は
It's bad luck for these people to come here
この人たちがここに来るのは不運だ
so they have to monitor
だから彼らは監視しなければならない
So we are at Datong Volcano
それで私たちは大同火山にいます
We're going to set up an observatory
天文台を設置する予定です
This is the hardware provided by the teaching staff of Yang Mingzhang
これはYang Mingzhangの教員が提供したハードウェアです
it's a nice environment
素敵な環境です
we borrowed here
私たちはここで借りました
Four or five Office
4 つまたは 5 つのオフィス
Then build this observatory
それからこの天文台を建ててください
good
良い
At the beginning, the Ministry of Science and Technology and the Ministry of the Interior
当初は科学技術省と内務省が
Because national industry belongs to the Ministry of the Interior
国家産業は内務省のものだから
We have a MEMO
MEMOがあります
and then construct this
あとはこれを構築するだけです
So the Ministry of Science and Technology paid the main money
それで科学技術省が主なお金を支払いました
Our Chinese is also the main person
私たちの中国人も主役です
not only me
私だけではありません
Many technicians at our Earth Institute
地球研究所には多くの技術者がいます
researchers participate in
研究者が参加する
Ministry of Science and Technology
科学技術省
The hardware equipment produced by the Ministry of the Interior
内務省が製造したハードウェア機器
Out of electricity, out of the house, out of these air conditioners
電気が切れて、家が切れて、エアコンが切れて
so we just
だから私たちはただ
Because this is not actually a
これは実際にはそうではないため、
Very simple one unit can perform
非常にシンプルな1台で実行可能
So we integrated a lot of
そこで私たちは多くの機能を統合しました
That's where our observatory's instruments are located
そこが私たちの天文台の機器がある場所です
That's the triangular fault just mentioned
それが先ほど述べた三角断層です
This is the entire area of Yangmingshan
ここは陽明山一帯です
Conceptually this picture is us on the surface
概念的には、この写真は地上にいる私たちです
Many different instruments were deployed
さまざまな機器が導入されました
Includes seismographs, crustal deformation, geochemistry, geothermal jets
地震計、地殻変動、地球化学、地熱ジェットが含まれます
I always hope that as long as the volcano has erupted before
以前に火山が噴火したことがある限り、私はいつもそう願っています
We believe that there should be some anomalies in these
これらには何らかの異常があるはずだと考えています
Then we have to report to the government, the people and everyone.
それから政府、国民、皆さんに報告しなければなりません。
Said the volcano may have started to restless
火山が落ち着きを失い始めたかもしれないと言った
That's our real-time monitoring station
それが私たちのリアルタイム監視ステーションです
So we send a lot of real-time news to this screen for discussion
そのため、ディスカッションのために多くのリアルタイム ニュースをこの画面に送信します
Then this picture is the enlarged one just now
では、この写真は今拡大したものです
This four-one picture is if people go up
この4-1の絵は人が上がれば
In fact, the surface and the crust will deform, right?
実際、表面や地殻は変形しますよね？
be raised or arched
盛り上がるかアーチ型になる
We'll just lean on the GPS to level the camp
GPS に頼ってキャンプを平らにするだけです
we can measure the deformation of its crust
地殻の変形を測定できます
And then here's like volcanic gas
そしてここには火山ガスのようなものがあります
Because its concentration composition will also change
濃度組成も変化しますので
It is conceivable that the temperature will also increase
気温も上がると思われます
special seismic activity
特別地震活動
Because my special session is doing earthquake activities
私の特別セッションは地震活動を行っているため
seismic activity is
地震活動は
Of course I know best
もちろん私が一番よく知っています
and I believe the most useful
そして私はそれが最も役に立つと信じています
a concept map
コンセプトマップ
I dont know if its usually 10 kilometers or 20 kilometers along the river.
通常は川沿いに10キロなのか20キロなのかわかりません。
Because there is heat along the river
川沿いは暑いので
So there's a little bit of an earthquake on it
それで少し地震が起きました
But if you run from A to B along the river like this
でもこうやって川に沿ってAからBまで走ったら
Only along the river will you run up
川に沿ってのみ駆け上がります
what will happen to this incredible thing
この信じられないことはどうなるでしょうか
Due to the change of temperature and pressure above
上記の温度と圧力の変化により、
There will be many, many earthquakes
たくさん地震が起こるだろう
For example
例えば
Our Yangmingshan is now a month
私たちの陽明山も一ヶ月になりました
There may be only 3 or 5 earthquakes every day
地震は毎日 3 回か 5 回しか起こらないかもしれない
If you run up the river
川を遡上すれば
i predict or i imagine
予測したり想像したりする
There may be 500 to 1000 earthquakes in one day
1日に500～1000回の地震が起こる可能性がある
That's obviously different
それは明らかに違うよ
Our record map secretly shows earthquakes
私たちの記録地図は密かに地震を示しています
But when you see it, it means that there is a follow-up action
しかし、それが表示されるということは、後続のアクションがあることを意味します
when it goes up
上がったとき
This is called a volcanic eruption.
これを火山噴火といいます。
But you can say from B to C
しかし、BからCまで言うことはできます
this earthquake
この地震
At B, the earthquake may be 3 kilometers away
B では、地震は 3 キロメートル離れたところにある可能性があります
1 kilometer left at C
C地点残り1キロ
Here maybe 5 kilometers or 10 kilometers
ここは5キロか10キロくらいかな
what does this mean
これは何を意味するのでしょうか
We only need the depth of the earthquake to determine it
地震の深さを判断するだけで十分です
Must slowly change from deep to front
深いところから手前にゆっくりと変化しなければなりません
it's maybe 20 days from here to here
ここからここまで多分20日くらい
I know it runs 0.5 kilometers a day
1日0.5キロ走るのは知っています
If it is 3 days from here to here
ここからここまで3日なら
I just saw it run 0.2km a day or something
1日0.2kmとか走っているのを見ました。
can i estimate
推定してもいいですか
I guess it's okay
大丈夫だと思います
That could be 10 days or a week to the surface
地上に現れるまで10日か1週間かかるかもしれない
so i can't tell you guys
だから皆さんには言えません
Will there be a volcanic eruption next year?
来年火山の噴火はありますか？
this time is too far
今回は遠すぎる
I can't follow
フォローできません
but
しかし
But if say a month the volcano will
しかし、たとえば 1 か月あれば、火山はそうなるだろう。
Volcano erupts in a month
火山は1か月以内に噴火する
I am sure I will see the exception
必ず例外が発生すると思います
I'll see a spike in these earthquakes
これらの地震は急増するだろう
Of course it's not just an earthquake.
もちろん地震だけではありません。
That is, the volcanic gas immediately deforms
つまり、火山ガスはすぐに変形します。
Low temperature, there should always be abnormalities in this
低温、これには必ず異常があるはずです
When integrated, there should be good information to judge
統合すると、判断に適した情報が得られるはずです
That also means that this is the approximate timeline
これは、これがおおよそのタイムラインであることも意味します
I can roughly estimate how long it might take to reach the surface
地表に到達するまでにどれくらい時間がかかるかを大まかに見積もることができます
Similarly, if I see Huangzui Mountain
同様に、黄瑞山を見たら
Earthquakes are coming out of Huangzui Mountain
黄嘴山から地震が起きています
I don't know that Huangzui Mountain may be delayed and approach the surface
黄瑞山が遅れて地表に近づく可能性があるかどうかはわかりません
If it is in Dayoukeng
大油坑なら
I'm a big travel pit
私は大の旅行好きです
so i know something
だから私は何かを知っています
Then if I see big tour pit and small tour pit
そして大きなツアーピット、小さなツアーピットが見えたら
Why is Huangzuishan what city?
なぜ黄瑞山は何の都市ですか？
The representative said wow, it was serious
代表者は「すごい、大変だった」と言いました
it's frontal, right?
それは正面ですよね？
So the size time
それで、サイズ時間
Probably scientifically, I can make an estimate
おそらく科学的に推定できるでしょう
So we did a lot of observations
そこで私たちはたくさんの観察をしました
But of course there have been no volcanic eruptions so far
しかし、もちろん、これまで火山の噴火はありませんでした
it's very lucky
それはとても幸運です
but we
しかし、我々
even without a volcanic eruption
火山の噴火がなくても
we do scientific research
私たちは科学研究を行っています
We still found a lot of interesting things
まだまだ面白いものをたくさん見つけました
what is interesting
何が面白いのか
We are Earthquake Warfare
私たちは地震戦争です
I will talk about the earthquake part
地震の部分について話します
this is
これは
Each line is a record of 24 hours a day
各行は 1 日 24 時間の記録です
A black is 15 minutes
ブラックは15分です
then blue for an hour
それから1時間ブルー
2 hours 24 hours
2時間 24時間
Show you 45 hours in the middle of the night
真夜中の45時間を見せて
The ground is shaking
地面が揺れています
First I saw this 10 years ago
初めてこれを見たのは10年前
I just want to say
言いたいだけ
that is the car
それは車です
what windswept hole
何という吹き抜けの穴
Anyway, there are many people in Yangmingshan
陽明山はとにかく人が多い
but i want to say
でも言いたい
The time pair is 10 o'clock in the middle of the night
時間は夜中の10時です
2:30 am
午前2時30分
impossible to have a car
車を持つことは不可能
unless it's something weird
何か変なことじゃない限り
That's science
それが科学です
we certainly believe
私たちは確かに信じています
believe in science
科学を信じます
So there should be no human activity
だから人間の活動はあってはならない
That should be this natural phenomenon
それがこの自然現象のはずだ
Because if the pot is heating it up,
なぜなら、鍋が加熱されていると、
when the pressure builds
圧力が高まったとき
The lid of the pot is not related to the steam
鍋の蓋は蒸気とは関係ありません
will it be a vibration
振動になるでしょうか
The vibration is likely to be caused by
振動の原因として考えられるのは、
The concept that the entire surface of the earth is shaking
地球の表面全体が揺れているという概念
That's also very interesting
それもとても興味深いですね
This is also an earthquake station
ここも地震観測所です
is one two three four
は 1、2、3、4 です
Just look at a dozen earthquake stations
十数個の地震観測所を見てみよう
send a signal at the same time
同時に信号を送る
Then this signal is called to look like a drop
次に、このシグナルが呼び出され、ドロップのように見えます。
This is the water drop shape in the scientific community
これは科学界における水滴の形です
an earthquake record
地震の記録
This is similar to the Chiayi Hualian earthquake
嘉義花蓮地震と似ていますね
completely different shape
全く違う形
Chiayi Hualian these earthquakes look
嘉義・花蓮の地震はこんな感じ
We look at P waves, S waves, and tangential body circles
P波、S波、接線方向の体円を観察します。
They all do this every day
彼らは皆これを毎日やっています
But this one can't see the P wave at all
しかし、これはP波がまったく見えません
S wave sees one
S波は1つを見る
It's just a very special energy in the shape of a water drop.
それは水滴のような特別なエネルギーです。
Then if you look closely at its frequency
次に、その周波数をよく見てみると、
that's more interesting
それはもっと面白いです
it is single frequency
それは単一周波数です
it's about three to a few hertz
およそ3ヘルツから数ヘルツです
single frequency signal
単一周波数信号
How can there be a single-frequency signal in nature?
自然界に単一周波数信号はどのようにして存在するのでしょうか?
this is incredible
これが信じられない
Of course it's simple. We want to say that everyone has played an instrument.
もちろん簡単なことですが、誰もが楽器を演奏したことがあると言いたいのです。
If you strip one of the strings, its a single fret, right?
弦を一本剥がしたらシングルフレットになりますよね？
That means it looks like someone is stripping a string in the ground
つまり、誰かが地面で糸を剥がしているように見えます
Of course it's impossible
もちろんそれは不可能です
Well, the real reason is
まあ、本当の理由は、
Because the magma under the ground actually has these cracks
地下のマグマには実際にこのような亀裂があるため、
When the gas or liquid in these cracks
この亀裂に気体や液体が入ると、
It just needs a change in pressure or a quick movement
圧力を変えるか素早い動作が必要なだけです
the whole rock wall will shake
岩壁全体が揺れるだろう
The frequency of shaking is determined by its width and length
揺れの周波数はその幅と長さによって決まります
like stripping a string
弦を剥ぐようなもの
If the thickness and length of its strings are fixed
紐の太さと長さが決まっている場合
its frequency is fixed
その周波数は固定されています
the width of the crack
亀裂の幅
Its geometry is the same it is a single frequency
形状は同じであり、単一周波数です
Then this is our real interpretation
それでは、これが私たちの本当の解釈です
It also has a shape like a screw
ネジのような形状もあります
super image screw
超像ネジ
called english they called Tonillos
英語で彼らはトニージョと呼んだ
this is
これは
This is very famous
これはとても有名です
Anyone who knows about volcanic earthquakes
火山性地震に詳しい方
Why
なぜ
In Central America just those volcanoes
中米にはまさにそれらの火山があります
when they often erupt
頻繁に噴火するとき
just see this first
まずはこれを見てください
How long does it take for the volcano to erupt after seeing this allergy?
このアレルギーが出てから火山が噴火するまでどれくらいかかりますか？
So this becomes
したがって、これは次のようになります
an indicator of a volcano in central america
中央アメリカの火山の指標
but can't say
でも言えない
Taiwan sees this volcanic eruption
台湾は今回の火山噴火を目撃
Because different volcanoes behave differently
火山が異なれば挙動も異なるため
some volcanic properties
いくつかの火山の性質
can be used as a reference
参考として使用できます
But what we saw on Dalun Mountain
しかし、私たちがダルン山で見たもの
Doesn't mean the volcano is going to erupt
火山が噴火するわけではない
but it represents
しかし、それは表します
Some properties of volcano activity
火山活動のいくつかの特性
Then it's more interesting to see how often
それから、どのくらいの頻度で
It is 2.1 4.2 6.3 8.4
2.1 4.2 6.3 8.4 です
just a few special ones
特別なものをいくつかだけ
This multiplied signal is just
この乗算された信号は、
Of course this is also a metaphor
もちろんこれも比喩です
like this
このような
You went to pluck the pipa and plucked three strings
あなたは笛を弾きに行き、三本の弦を弾きました
Three different frequencies come out
3つの異なる周波数が出ます
Of course there can't be
もちろんそんなことはありえない
these choices
これらの選択
the same is
同じです
you also have a
あなたも持っています
extended to different enshrining times
合祀時期が異なる
A column Bong is a frequency
列ボンは周波数です
Column B is the frequency of series Bong
列 B は系列 Bong の頻度です。
it has since been blown to words
それ以来、それは言葉に吹き飛ばされました
When you bite it, it will come out with some fixed frequency
噛むと一定の頻度で出てきます
that also has this low frequency
それもこの低周波を持っています
In fact, its frequency is very low
実はその頻度は非常に低いのです
That's also very classic
それもとても古典的ですね
The usual breakthrough volcanic eruption just mentioned
先ほど述べた通常の画期的な火山噴火
Do it for me on January 17th
1月17日に私のためにやってください
About 10 days before the eruption
噴火の約10日前
they see these things
彼らはこれらのことを見ます
Hundreds of low-frequency earthquakes came out
低周波地震が何百回も出た
then finally they explained
それから最後に彼らは説明しました
When the magma runs in the cracks of the rock
マグマが岩の割れ目に流れ込むとき
low frequency signal
低周波信号
So it's also a good indicator
したがって、それは良い指標でもあります
if dalun chapter we see a lot of this
ダルン章ならこれをたくさん見ることができます
It's also a big warning sign
それは大きな危険信号でもあります
There is also this Cheung Chau class
こんな長州クラスもあります
In fact, there are quite a lot of pigs of this kind.
実際、この種の豚はたくさんいます。
I will speed up a little bit
少しずつスピードアップしていきます
Okay, then let's take the original chairperson
はい、それでは元の議長に行きましょう
this confession
この告白
Academician Li Rouxuan
学術研究員 リー・ロウシュアン
Later, our Institute of Earth Sciences
その後、私たちの地球科学研究所は、
Rescue director
レスキューディレクター
After he is here as the chief committee member,
彼が主任委員としてここに来てから、
Let's finish this Volcano Watching Station
この火山監視所を終わらせましょう
Of course, the mission of the Volcano Watching Station is mainly for volcanic disasters
もちろん、火山監視所の使命は主に火山災害です。
But it actually seems to be a negative
でも実際はマイナスな気がする
But there are also positive
しかし、ポジティブな面もあります
This volcanic resource, geothermal development
この火山資源、地熱開発
In fact, they are two sides of the same body.
実際、それらは同じ体の表裏の関係にあります。
If we take these magma
このマグマを取ったら
These geothermal surveys are clear
これらの地熱調査は明らかです
In fact, it can be applied
実は応用できるんです
Are those two Yamadas successful?
あの山田二人は成功しているのか？
what is the back garden
裏庭とは何ですか
very beautiful natural landscape
とても美しい自然の風景
that also has fumaroles
それも噴気孔がある
The hole of exile is a landscape unique to these volcanoes
流刑の穴はこの火山特有の風景です
different time periods
さまざまな期間
Huang Wen during the day
日中の黄温
very beautiful
非常に美しい
These are some photos taken by our TVO colleagues over there
これらは、TVO の同僚が向こうで撮った写真です
It has snowed in the past two years
ここ2年で雪が降りました
It's also very rare
それもとても珍しいです
Snow scene throughout our TVO
TVO ではずっと雪のシーンが続いています
that hot spring
あの温泉
After having these beautiful landscapes
この美しい風景を見た後は
if again
またしたら
Development of hot springs Development of Sidan
温泉開発 シダン開発
An area that can provide better tourism, leisure and vacation
より良い観光・レジャー・休暇を提供できるエリア
That's these snow monkeys in Hokkaido, Japan
それが北海道のスノーモンキーです
They also know to take a hot spring when it's cold
彼らは寒いときは温泉に入るのが良いことも知っている
The largest geothermal development is Iceland
最大の地熱開発はアイスランド
In fact, besides enjoying these hot springs, Iceland
実は、アイスランドはこれらの温泉を楽しむだけでなく、
They are also the world's geothermal development
それらは世界の地熱開発でもあります
Probably more than 80% of Iceland's energy is geothermal.
おそらくアイスランドのエネルギーの 80% 以上は地熱です。
so they don't need a nuclear power plant
だから原子力発電所は要らない
Nuclear power plants don't need to burn coal
原子力発電所は石炭を燃やす必要がない
they enjoy the natural
彼らは自然を楽しんでいます
Since Taiwan has these volcanic geothermal
台湾には火山性地熱があるので、
In fact, we should do some work on the concept
実際、このコンセプトについてもう少し作業を行う必要があります
So will continental volcanoes have geothermal development?
では、大陸の火山でも地熱は発達するのでしょうか？
In addition to this volcanic construction
この火山構造に加えて、
In fact, I also spent some time doing these tasks.
実際、私もこれらの作業に時間を費やしました。
We put up some seismic stations that look like
次のような地震観測所をいくつか設置しました。
There seems to be a big one here
ここに大きいのがありそうだ
Hot discussion storage area
ホットなディスカッションの保管エリア
If the science above this should be specifically
これを超える科学が具体的にあるべきであるならば、
Earthquake opening should be a good place
地震開口部は良い場所であるはずです
But don't believe it's in a national park
でもここが国立公園内だなんて信じないでください
This environmental protection regulation may also design customer service
この環境保護規制は顧客サービスも設計する可能性があります
But anyway this is
でもとにかくこれは
Anyway, based on science, we can do some related things
とにかく、科学に基づいて、私たちはいくつかの関連したことを行うことができます
good
良い
The map part is more fun
マップ部分がさらに楽しい
this voice
この声
This is actually the media or something
これは実際にはメディアか何かです
you may have the impression
という印象があるかもしれません
say in a while
しばらくすると言う
someone heard a strange sound
誰かが奇妙な音を聞いた
then this is
それならこれは
15 years is
15年というのは
someone heard something
誰かが何かを聞いた
anyway some description
とにかく何らかの説明
it means sound
それは音を意味します
someone over here heard
ここで誰かが聞いた
In fact, when the media came to ask us
実際、メディアが私たちに質問しに来たとき、
Actually, I probably have a clue
実際のところ、私にはおそらく手がかりがある
But at that time it was not well organized
しかし当時はまだ組織化されていなかった
so just pretend not to know
だから知らないふりをしてください
But now I probably know
でも今ならきっとわかる
also in history
歴史の中でも
You see, this is 1835 and 53 years
ほら、これは 1835 年と 53 年です
next day big butt
次の日大きなお尻
three days
3日
it will be very noisy
とても騒がしいでしょう
then we
それから私たち
Since we do these our TBO colleagues
私たちはこれらを行っているので、TBOの同僚
Now I often call and say
今ではよく電話してこう言います
The teacher often hears place names today
先生は今日地名をよく聞きます
It's just that some people can hear it and some people can't.
ただ聞こえる人もいれば聞こえない人もいるというだけです。
of course you really
もちろんあなたは本当に
some say some don't
言わない人もいる
is there any
何かありますか
this
これ
we rely on evidence
私たちは証拠に依存します
There are of course many reasons for place names
もちろん地名の由来はいろいろありますが、
There are places with earthquakes and various guitars
地震やいろんなギターがある場所もある
Today we will talk about the place names of volcanoes
今日は火山の地名についてお話します。
This is our sacrifice
これは私たちの犠牲です
this is about five minutes long
これは約5分です
but I say it as
でも私はこう言います
probably no more than five seconds
おそらく5秒以内
the reason is because
その理由は、
when everyone listens for five minutes
みんなが5分間聞いたら
probably fell asleep
おそらく眠ってしまったのでしょう
The first reason is to say
一つ目の理由はこう言うことです
if five minutes ago
5分前なら
In fact, its frequency is very low
実はその頻度は非常に低いのです
you can't hear
聞こえません
because our ears are from
私たちの耳は
20Hz to 20,000Hz
20Hz～20,000Hz
normal person
正常人
If it is 10Hz
10Hzであれば
we can't hear
私たちには聞こえません
just too low frequency
ただ周波数が低すぎる
or too high frequency
または周波数が高すぎる
So for everyone to hear
だからみんなに聞いてもらえるように
I'll take it a little
ちょっと引き受けます
This is called a dead sound
これをデッドサウンドといいます
turn five minutes into five seconds
5分を5秒に変える
this is overclocking
これはオーバークロックです
But the five flavors are like a plane flying past
でも5つのフレーバーはまるで飛行機が通り過ぎていくようだ
but
しかし
We use these signals
私たちはこれらの信号を使用します
Actually, you see, this is a different kind of earthquake warfare
実は、これは別の種類の地震戦です
Why Earthquake Warfare Receives Sound
なぜ地震戦が響き渡るのか
In fact, the sound is the vibration of air
実は音は空気の振動なのです
air shaken to the surface
空気が表面に揺れる
our ruins on the surface
地上の私たちの遺跡
Shake our relics too
私たちの遺物も振ってください
because of shaking the ground
地面が揺れるから
shake relics
遺物を振る
So let's remember the signals
だから信号を覚えましょう
We can see these earthquake shadows
この地震の影が見えます
You see this is every earthquake video received
これが受信したすべての地震ビデオです
Then we according to its sequence
次に、その順序に従って
we can go and find out where it is
私たちは行ってそれがどこにあるかを見つけることができます
Like this example, we found it in Xiaoniu Pit
この例のように、小牛坑で発見されました。
very clear
非常に明確な
I don't know if it's here or here
ここなのかここなのか分からない
perhaps
多分
The difference may be 10 meters 50 meters
その差は10メートル50メートルかもしれません
but not going outside the calf pit
ただしふくらはぎの穴の外には出ない
anyway
ともかく
Shanhui is also here
シャンフイもここにいます
Sure
確定
This is just about one hundred and two minutes
ここまではちょうど 102 分ほどです
I put it like two seconds
2秒くらい置いた
you will hear
聞くでしょう
Actually look carefully at this
実はこれをよく見てください
In fact, this picture alone wrote an article on this
実はこの写真だけで記事が書けました。
This scientific international article
この国際的な科学論文
I talked about this this is
これについて話しました、これは
this is time
これは時間です
this is the frequency
これが周波数です
This is when the whole thing explodes
これはイメージ全体が爆発するときです
before the explosion
爆発の前に
It has frequencies from seventy grammes all the way down to almost forty grammes
周波数は70グラムからほぼ40グラムまであります。
The frequency keeps going back and forth
周波数は行ったり来たりを繰り返す
then give it a blast
それからそれを爆発させてください
Actually very simple description
実はとても簡単な説明
It's like playing that heavy sky cannon when I was a child
子供の頃に重い天空砲で遊んでいたようなものだ
You chirp at one point and it explodes in the sky
ある時点で鳴くと、それは空で爆発します
That's certainly not a heavy sky cannon
それは決して重い空砲ではありません
This actually has good physics behind it
これには実際に優れた物理学が裏付けられています
Then we probably don't have time to talk about deeper things.
そうなると、もっと深いことを話す時間がなくなるかもしれません。
In fact, Xiaoerkeng often records these things
実際、Xiaoerkeng はこれらのことを頻繁に記録します
That child's pit is more interesting
あの子のピットの方が面白い
This is the location of the children's pit
児童ピットの場所はこちら
You went to Xiaoerkeng to play Qiqisan and climbed up
あなたは七岐山をするために小爾坑に行き、登った
this is the trail
これが道です
You can see these little pits along the trail
トレイル沿いに小さな穴が見えます
Then it actually becomes a series of cracks
そして実際につながって一連の亀裂ができた
How did these cracks come about?
この亀裂はどのようにして生じたのでしょうか?
In fact, I know how some place names come from.
実際、私はいくつかの地名の由来を知っています。
Actually this is every
実はこれは毎度のことです
It was just the result of the explosion that looked like Chongtian helping him
爆発の結果、チョンティアンが彼を助けたように見えました
I mean this small pit
この小さな穴のことを言います
Of course not with time
もちろん時間の関係ではありません
In turn it is a gas explosion from within
今度は内部からのガス爆発です
It's when there's a lot of pressure underneath
根底に大きなプレッシャーがかかっているときです
It instantly exploded like a hole
一瞬にして穴があいたように爆発した
So it's just a hole along this fault line
つまり、それはこの断層線に沿った単なる穴です
hole by hole
一つの穴 一つの穴
geological age has been
地質時代は
explode again
また爆発する
That's how it stays on the surface
そうやって表面に残るんだよ
So if you examine this entire fracture hole
この骨折穴全体を調べてみると
These are all one by one
これらはすべて一つ一つです
It seems that this is connected with those in Shikeng
これは石坑のものと関係があるようです。
very very many
非常非常多
The rep says it's actually been active
担当者は実際に活動していると言っています
It's just that we haven't paid attention to it
ただ私たちがそれに気づいていないだけなのです
Generally speaking, we say that volcanic eruptions are magma.
一般に火山の噴火はマグマであると言われます。
Like this steam explosion just looks like that explosion sound that's it
この水蒸気爆発はあの爆発音に似てる、それだけだ
Then this kind is like Hawaii, or many of them are hot sun to the surface with lava and broken rust flow
そして、この種はハワイのようなもの、またはそれらの多くは、溶岩と壊れた錆の流れで地表に熱い太陽が降り注いでいます
What about this one? It's like Kaohsiung gas explosion
これはどうですか? 高雄のガス爆発みたいなものです
It explodes, only the power of this door's cauldron explodes
爆発する この扉の大釜の力だけが爆発する
Then don't say it doesn't seem threatening.
それなら、脅威ではないとは言わないでください。
January 3, 2014 he was a steam explosion
2014 年 1 月 3 日、彼は水蒸気爆発でした
He also caused the deaths of more than 60 people
彼はまた60人以上の死者を出した
That death is really unfortunate
その死は本当に残念だ
this is autumn, then noon, then it's saturday
これは秋、そして正午、そして土曜日です
Because this January 3rd is like our Central Mountain Range, there are usually no people living nearby
今年の1月3日は私たちの中央山脈のようなものなので、普段は近くに人が住んでいません。
But the autumn wind is also super beautiful, a bunch of people went hiking on Saturday
でも秋の風もとても綺麗で、土曜日はたくさんの人がハイキングに行きました
Then when they run to the top of the mountain, their habit is to go to the top of the mountain
そして、山の頂上まで走るとき、彼らの習慣は山の頂上に行くことです
You have to go to the top of the mountain before noon, and come down after eating some steam or bento
昼前に山頂に行き、湯気やお弁当を食べてから下山しなければなりません
Everyone near noon is at 3
正午近くの人は全員3時です
As a result, the explosion at that time
その結果、その時の爆発は、
That's why sixty or seventy
だから60とか70とか
if he is monday
彼が月曜日なら
or 3 p.m.
または午後3時
a cat is fine
猫は大丈夫です
this is such an unfortunate thing
これはとても残念なことです
just listen to this
これを聞いてください
This is two when we count
数えてみるとこれは2つです
You said it sounded like a bird chirping
鳥のさえずりみたいだと君は言った
like the people of the forest
森の人々のように
this one is slightly longer
これは少し長いです
about two minutes
約2分
In fact, I have collected a lot of these
実は、これをたくさん集めたんです
no i can't come in
いいえ、入れません
This is like a train
これは電車のようです
played the sound of a train
電車の音を鳴らした
This image is staring at me
この画像は私を見つめています
that's good
それは良い
Then this giant viewer just now actually
それから、この巨大な視聴者は今実際に
From now on I will write another article
これからまた別の記事を書きます
Just talking about this is a volcano conversation.
これについて話すだけでは火山の会話です。
In fact, it is one by one
実は一つ一つです
This Jet Arch Happened Another is this one
このジェットアーチが起きました もう一つはこれです
So A and B are over there
AとBはあそこにいるよ
It's super fun to sing along
一緒に歌うととても楽しいです
It's the dialogue of the volcano
それは火山の対話です
Then this is Zhongshan Luo and Ziping after spraying
これがスプレー後の中山羅と紫平です
Then it's like the two are talking
そしたら二人で話してるようだった
The last one is
最後は
Dean Guoyu
國瑜院長
This is a piece of Dean Guoyu
これはディーン・グオユウの作品です
I'll skip it first
最初はスキップします
That's Dean Guoyu
それはディーン・グオユーです
See me these volcano sounds
火山の音を見てください
He went to find that one called Art Association
彼は芸術協会という団体を探しに行きました
This is the performance art
これがパフォーマンスアートです
He said this voice can be used as background
この声は背景として使えるとのこと
Then they played for two hours
それから彼らは2時間遊びました
Then I listen to this wow this is wonderful
それからこれを聴きます、すごいですね
This is the combination of science and humanities
これは科学と人文科学の組み合わせです
good last volcano heartbeat
良い最後の火山の鼓動
Then we have SeismicNet and we can record a lot of earthquakes
SeismicNet があれば、たくさんの地震を記録できます
That earthquake was nothing special
あの地震は何でもなかった
But the funny thing is that we are here in Dayoukeng
しかし面白いのは、私たちがここ大油坑にいるということです。
recorded hundreds of earthquakes
何百もの地震を記録
So what's so special about this earthquake?
では、この地震の何が特別なのでしょうか?
This is the new electrogram
これが新しい電気記録図です
Then every black line here is
すると、ここにあるすべての黒い線は、
This one is an earthquake station
ここは地震観測所です
Then every earthquake will have a
そうすれば、すべての地震には
just an earthquake
ただの地震
So when an earthquake occurs
それで、地震が起きたとき、
Received all the brochures
パンフレットをすべて受け取りました
Then this bar and bar is an earthquake
そして、このバーが次々と地震です
For example, just look at a single one.
たとえば、1 つだけを見てみましょう。
single brochure you see
あなたが見ている単一のパンフレット
When each vertical bar
それぞれの縦棒が
just a small earthquake
ほんの小さな地震
Then this small earthquake turned out to be periodic
その後、この小さな地震は周期的であることが判明しました
Hualian earthquake
花蓮地震
probably no one can understand
おそらく誰も理解できないでしょう
when will the next earthquake occur
次の地震はいつ起こりますか
but here i go with you
でもここで私はあなたと一緒に行きます
Now there's another 18 minutes
あと18分ある
At 18 minutes, here are the statistics
18 分後の統計は次のとおりです
Of course not by a few seconds
もちろん数秒の差ではありません
There will be one in 18 or 19 minutes
18分か19分後に1本あります
This is about 1, 200 earthquakes
これは約1,200回の地震に相当します
every 18 minutes
18分ごと
We know our heartbeat is 7, 80 beats per minute
私たちの心拍数は毎分 7、80 拍であることがわかっています
But you count about 18 minutes, 7, 80 times a day
でも、1日に18分、7、80回数えます。
This means it dances very slowly
これは非常にゆっくりと踊ることを意味します
But it is more interesting to say, when did this heartbeat start
しかし、もっと興味深いのは、この心拍がいつ始まったかということです。
It is from a 4.8 earthquake in Hualien
花蓮で起きたマグニチュード4.8の地震です。
When the earthquake reached Yang Mingshan
地震が陽明山に到達したとき
Then the heart starts beating
それから心臓が鼓動し始める
it's not moby jump
それは白鯨ジャンプではありません
It is as if someone is going to wake it up, bite it
まるで誰かが起こして噛んでくるみたいだ
It's time for a heartbeat
心臓の鼓動の時間です
Then I'll... this is another earthquake in Taichung
それから私は...これは台中でまた地震です
3.7, as soon as the earthquake comes
3.7、地震が来るとすぐに
Bobo Bobo, the heartbeat is coming
ボボボーボ、鼓動が来る
it happened three times
それは3回起こりました
Although it's only three times, I'm super excited
たった3回だけどすごく楽しみです
How come... Earthquakes are periodic
どうして...地震は周期的に起こるのですか
It's the whole world... I never mentioned it
それが世界のすべてだ...私はそれについて決して言及しなかった
then i will make a metaphor
それから私は比喩をします
This is the normal heartbeat
これが正常な心拍数です
Then there's a heart problem
それから心臓に問題がある
Start trimmer, start jumping wildly, don't jump at all
トリマーを開始し、激しくジャンプし始めます、まったくジャンプしません
then jump again
それからまたジャンプする
Then sent to the hospital, of course the electric shock
その後病院に送られ、当然電気ショックを受けました
He will jump up after the electric shock
彼は感電後に飛び上がるだろう
So the earthquake Taichung machine in Hualien
それで花蓮の台中地震機
like electric shock
感電のような
So Yangmingshan may be broken
だから陽明山は壊れるかもしれない
It's just that my heart hasn't jumped for a long time
ただ、長い間心が躍っていなかったんだ
The earthquake shocked it and made him start jumping
地震の衝撃で彼は飛び跳ねた
That's a metaphor
それは比喩です
not really the case
実際にはそうではない
A fun thing is
楽しいことは、
This heartbeat will kill
この鼓動が人を殺すだろう
The little mouse jumped hundreds of times
小さなネズミは何百回もジャンプしました
his life is short
彼の人生は短い
Elephants are good at jumping very slowly
ゾウはゆっくりとジャンプするのが得意です
then live longer
それから長生きしてください
Of course that person is no longer an animal?
もちろん、その人はもう動物ではありませんか？
People are no longer in this ordinary animal
人間はもはやこの普通の動物ではありません
This quote means
この引用の意味は、
Anyway, the faster the heartbeat, the shorter the life
とにかく心拍数が速いほど寿命は短くなる
Well if this extends it to volcanoes
これを火山にまで拡張すると
those 18 minutes
その18分
it's jumping super slow super slow
超ゆっくり超ゆっくりジャンプしてる
So it can live for a long time
だから長生きできるんだよ
I'm not scientific
私は科学者ではありません
a bit silly
ちょっとばかげた
ok then the last summary
はい、それでは最後のまとめです
Let's go back to Daping Mountain
大坪山に戻りましょう
with this
これとともに
This vulgar position may
この下品な立場は、
Metropolis and Old Town of Taipei
台北の大都市と旧市街
This Taipei city is a million people
この台北市は人口100万人です
Of course the Vulgar position
もちろん下品なところはここです
Pompeii has 20,000 people
ポンペイの人口は2万人
This is much worse
これはさらに悪いことです
That's about 10 kilometers away.
それは約10キロメートル離れています。
are very similar distances
非常に似た距離です
that is volcanic
それは火山です
this big east volcano
この大きな東の火山
This date may be 6000 years
この日付は6000年前かもしれない
But the Vulgarian position was actually sprayed again in 1914
しかし、ブルガリアの立場は実際には 1914 年に再びスプレーされました。
The heights of the Qixing Mountain and the Vulgar Seat are actually over 1,000.
七星山と俗位置の高さは実際には1,000を超えています
That's mainly interesting
それは主に興味深いことです
The area of our magma household is about 70 square kilometers
私たちのマグマの家の面積は約70平方キロメートルです
Ordinary position about 400
通常位置 約400
In fact, it is 6 or 7 times larger
実際は6～7倍くらい大きいです
6 times is actually bigger
実際は6倍のほうが大きい
Volcano is getting bigger
火山が大きくなっている
It's shallower too
それも浅いよ
So we go a little deeper
それで、もう少し深く進んでいきます
but we are trying now
しかし、私たちは今努力しています
Find another 5 kilometers and 10 kilometers of magma chambers
さらに5キロメートルと10キロメートルのマグマだまりを見つける
This is what we have been doing for the last few years
これが私たちがここ数年やってきたことです
Historical disasters, of course, this side is also very scary
歴史的災害はもちろんこちら側もとても怖いです
But Yangmingshan did not
しかし陽明山はそうではなかった
The last one is what we want to convey today
最後は今日伝えたいこと
Whether it's a big volcano or a small volcano
大きな火山でも小さな火山でも
Population nearby or far away
近隣または遠方の人口
In fact, in the past, science can tell us
実際、過去には科学が私たちに教えてくれました。
You just have to do something very easy to monitor
非常に簡単に監視できることを行うだけです
There is probably a considerable degree of protection
おそらくかなりの保護力があると思われます
That monitoring is scientifically speaking
モニタリングは科学的に言えば
that is very simple
それはとても簡単です
You just put the ruins down for some analysis and sorting.
分析と分類のために遺跡を置くだけです。
and then probably give us some
そしておそらく私たちに何かをくれるでしょう
good reference relic
良い参考遺物
The ancient city of Navisbowei is here
古代都市ナビス・ボウイはここにあります
But Napoli so they keep doing it
しかし、ナポリはそれを続ける
This is a volcanic city
ここは火山都市です
cities on or around volcanoes
火山の上またはその周囲の都市
That Taipei is also a volcano
台北も火山だということ
one of the volcano cities
火山都市の一つ
The question is, will the volcano move?
問題は、火山が動くかどうかです。
we do not know
我々は知りません
but we have to be prepared
しかし、私たちは準備をしなければなりません
if one day it moves
いつかそれが動くなら
we need to know in advance
事前に知っておく必要があります
That's the job of going to the Volcano Watch to fight
それが火山監視所に行って戦う仕事だ
So a simple question
そこで簡単な質問です
I am often asked by many people
いろんな人からよく聞かれるんですが
So maybe now you guys can answer
それで、もう答えられるかもしれません
Will the first one be active
1人目は活躍するのか
Yes
はい
I usually don't even think about it
普段はなんとも思わないのですが
i usually want to say
普通に言いたいのですが
can not rule out
除外することはできません
more like this
もっとこのように
Then the second is to say
次に、2番目はこう言います
Spending money will be interesting
お金の使い方が面白くなる
yes
はい
everyone trust me
みんな私を信頼してる
I often go around giving speeches to people
私はよく人々の前でスピーチをしに行きます
that's it
それでおしまい
But actually I'm pretty stressed when I go home
でも実際は家に帰るとかなりストレスになるんです
the day the volcano erupts
火山が噴火する日
I still haven't told everyone
まだみんなには伝えてないけど
I might
私はかもしれない
Might have to kill myself like this
このまま自殺するしかないかもしれない
And where did the millions of citizens flee to?
そして何百万もの国民はどこへ逃げたのでしょうか？
This is the section chief of the exercise in Taipei
こちらは台北演習の課長です
You keep checking on me, just asking what to do? What should Mr. Lin do?
あなたは私をチェックし続けて、どうすればいいですか? リンさんは何をすべきですか?
He said where are our six million people going? I said don't scare yourself
彼は「600万人の国民はどこへ行くの？」と言いました。私は「怖がらないでください」と言いました。
There is no such thing as six million people, right?
600万人なんて存在しないですよね？
Then Qiandu also wanted to say that we should move to Taichung.
それから銭都も台中に移るべきだと言いたかったのです。
The last question has an answer
最後の質問には答えがあります
We should not be in the ancient city next to us
私たちは隣の古代都市にいるべきではありません
Except for many natural conditions, the most important and the least
多くの自然条件を除いて、最も重要で最も重要でないものは、
Reality and space are different, there was no science two thousand years ago
現実と宇宙は違う、二千年前には科学はなかった
people don't know what's going on
人々は何が起こっているのか分かりません
but we now have science
しかし今では科学があります
Science can tell us many answers
科学は多くの答えを教えてくれます
So the simple answer is no
したがって、単純な答えはノーです
So it's festival
ということでお祭りです
It means that we will live and die with the volcano.
それは私たちが火山とともに生き、火山とともに死ぬことを意味します。
but through science
しかし科学を通して
Finally, I would like to thank the relevant units
最後に、関係各所に感謝の意を表したいと思います。
Because this plan has actually been in the works for more than ten years.
なぜなら、この計画は実は10年以上も前から進められていたからです。
It's this big plan that has been in the works for more than ten years.
この大規模な計画は 10 年以上にわたって進められてきました。
not a single one
一つもありません
This department or Chinese can also pay for all this
この部門か中国人でもこれらすべての費用を支払うことができます
So we use various channels
そのため、さまざまなチャネルを使用します
Then go to persuade people to give money to people
それから人々にお金を与えるように人々を説得しに行きます
So let's build this bounce off the battle
それで、戦闘からのこの跳ね返りを構築しましょう
Okay, sorry for the delay.
さて、遅くなってごめんなさい。
thanks, thanks
どうもどうも
Well we thank you researcher for a very good presentation
研究者、とても良いプレゼンテーションをしてくれてありがとう
Now the rest of our time is open to questions
残りの時間は質疑応答です
We have prepared exquisite gifts on site
素敵なプレゼントをその場でご用意しております
hand over here
ここに渡してください
We have ten, so the first ten
10 個あるので、最初の 10 個
If the first ten people ask questions, they will get a small gift
先着10名様に質問すると粗品をプレゼント
There's that microphone in front of you guys
皆さんの前にマイクがあります
wait a minute please use the microphone if you want to ask a question
ちょっと待ってください、質問したい場合はマイクを使ってください
click that one
それをクリックしてください
green part
緑色の部分
This will turn the microphone on
これによりマイクがオンになります
good
良い
now please
現在請問
what's your problem
あなたの問題は何ですか
good
良い
here
ここ
Hello Mr. Lin
こんにちは、リンさん
good
良い
Actually what I want to ask is
実は聞きたいのは
if a warning occurs say
警告が発生した場合は言う
There will be a big earthquake in the next ten days
今後10日以内に大きな地震が起こるでしょう
there will be a volcanic eruption
火山の噴火が起こるだろう
no results
検索結果はありません
seems more serious
もっと深刻なようです
like a typhoon
台風のように
put a fake result
偽の結果を載せる
No, my question is actually
いいえ、私の質問は実際には
The characteristics of the Big Butt Volcano and other
ビッグバット火山の特徴とその他
other volcanoes
他の火山
For example, the volcanic nature of Hawaii
たとえば、ハワイの火山性
Is there any difference
違いはありますか
In other words, just ten days ago
つまり、ちょうど10日前に
That dense vibration thing
あの濃密な振動のこと
Big Butt Volcano
ビッグバット火山
we have no way to prove
証明する方法がありません
really like that
本当にそうだね
Will time really explode in the future?
将来、時間は本当に爆発するのでしょうか？
unless it really explodes
本当に爆発しない限り
That experience comes from
その経験はから来ています
Hawaiian Volcanoes
ハワイの火山
Will they be the same
それらは同じでしょうか
still may be different
まだ違うかもしれない
Thanks
ありがとう
this is a very good question
これはとても良い質問です
and you're an insider
そしてあなたはインサイダーです
the volcanic issue
火山の問題
Actually not 100%
実は100％ではない
And every volcano behaves differently
そして、火山ごとに挙動が異なります
In fact, the Hawaiian volcano and Mount Fuji
実はハワイの火山と富士山は
Or that actually the volcano has very
あるいは、実際に火山には非常に大きな影響があるということです。
many kinds
多種
Shrimp meat is also relatively viscous magma
エビの身も比較的粘度の高いマグマです
so it just won't explode
だから爆発しないだけ
This one was blasted
こいつは爆破された
It actually flows more like water
実際は水のように流れます
That's like this volcano in the Pacific Rim
それは環太平洋の火山のようなものです
it will explode like
みたいに爆発するだろう
That's because of its viscosity
それは粘度のせいです
Or we say its acid-base scientifically
または、科学的には酸塩基と言います。
Its ratio of that SIO2
そのSIO2の比率
you can imagine that
それは想像できます
as a pot of water
水の入ったポットとして
Shrimp meat is like a pot of water
エビの身は鍋の水のようなもの
when you add it
それを追加するとき
the water will roll
水が転がるだろう
But if you cook a pot of porridge
しかし、鍋でお粥を調理すると、
or corn chowder with words
または言葉付きのコーンチャウダー
When the viscosity is high
粘度が高い場合
you boil boil boil it will
あなたは沸騰します沸騰沸騰するでしょう
it will
そうなる
right
右
it's sticky
ベタベタしている
it accumulates energy all the time
それは常にエネルギーを蓄積します
then it's about to explode
それから爆発寸前です
so different volcanoes
とても違う火山
In fact, its composition is different
実は成分が違うんです
it behaves differently
それは動作が異なります
So we can't put shrimp flavor
なのでエビ風味は入れられません
or usually by fire
または通常は火によって
Any volcanic act takes
いかなる火山活動も
Predicting what will happen to our big volcanoes
私たちの大きな火山に何が起こるかを予測する
In fact, to put it bluntly, everyone
実は、はっきり言ってみんな
or everyone volcano
あるいはみんな火山
has its own unique personality
独自の個性を持っています
We want to predict the behavior of a person
人の行動を予測したい
We can't put A's person's
Aさんの人のものは入れられない
past to predict B's
B を予測するための過去
In fact, the risk is great
実はリスクが大きい
We better do it for A
Aのためにやったほうがいいよ
good observation
良い観察
See how his behavior tends to be
彼がどのように振る舞うかを見てください
Then we make predictions based on the strategy
次に、戦略に基づいて予測を行います
But even then we can't
でも、それでもできない
In fact, there are several volcanoes that say
実際、次のように言う火山がいくつかあります。
I thought it would erupt, but it didn't
噴火するかと思ったけど噴火しなかった
this is
これは
Sometimes for a very simple reason
時には非常に単純な理由で
Your magma keeps moving up and down
あなたのマグマは上下に動き続けます
Successors are unreasonable. In fact, Mount Fuji used to be
後継者には無理がある 実は富士山も昔は
this 2001
この2001年
Japanese scientists and the government
日本の科学者と政府
is nervous as hell
めちゃくちゃ緊張している
Why do they earthquake from 20 km
なぜ20キロメートルから地震が起きるのか
I have been running and running for 2 kilometers
2キロほど走って走ってました
He thought it might come up tomorrow or the day after tomorrow
彼はそれが明日か明後日になるかもしれないと思った
be quiet from now on
これからは静かにしてください
So it's still his
だからそれはまだ彼のもの
this uncertainty
この不確実性
We can only do it by looking at the skills
スキルを見てやるしかない
yes
はい
It is the shadow of the S wave and the phantom of the P wave that you mentioned earlier
先ほどおっしゃったS波の影とP波の幻です。
These are the two phenomena of smoke and phantom arrival
煙と幻の到来という二つの現象です
Then these two phenomena are what I just said from the teacher.
それから、この二つの現象は今先生から申し上げたとおりでございます。
I think all I know is that it reflects that it is a representative book
私が知っているのは、それが代表的な本であることを反映しているということだけだと思います
There is a liquid substance in the ground
地面には液体の物質が存在する
How can we infer from the existence of this liquid substance?
では、この液体物質の存在からどのように推測できるのでしょうか。
It is possible to estimate the volume of the magma chamber and its depth
マグマだまりの体積や深さの推定が可能
Is this information? Thanks
これは情報ですか? ありがとう
The volume is based on the presence or absence of side stations on our surface
ボリュームは、地表上のサイドステーションの有無に基づいています。
We can roughly outline a range
大まかに範囲を概説することができます
that depth is a good question
その深さは良い質問です
Depth because of more scientific issues
より科学的な問題による深み
That is to say, I didn't talk much here.
つまり、ここではあまり話さなかったのですが、
That is to say, I use earthquakes at different depths for cross-comparison
つまり、相互比較のために異なる深さの地震を使用します。
There is a little bit of this depth past and this depth
この深さの過去とこの深さは少しだけあります
If cut to yes or no
「はい」または「いいえ」にカットされた場合
It has an angle, right?
角度がありますよね？
If at the very surface it doesn't have both
表面的には両方を持っていない場合
because it is kilometers
キロメートルあるから
start to have a little gap
少し隙間ができ始める
So take it slow
だからゆっくりしてください
Of course this is just an estimate
もちろんこれは単なる推定です
That's why we have our second big plan.
だからこそ私たちは第二の大きな計画を立てています。
Hope to make more accurate
より正確になることを願っています
So something like this
それで、このようなもの
At present, the preliminary results can only reach this
現時点では、暫定結果はこれまでしか到達できません
yes
はい
because probably the whole world
なぜならおそらく全世界が
I think I'm the first to do this
これをやったのは私が初めてだと思う
Because like Mount Fuji
富士山みたいだから
Actually theirs or Hasber Mountain
実際、彼らやハスバー山は
they are very clear
彼らはとても明確です
What's in store along the river
川沿いには何があるのか
the evidence is very clear
証拠は非常に明確です
people don't need to do this
人々はこれを行う必要はありません
That's because it's too controversial in Taiwan
台湾では物議を醸しすぎているから
We can't see that thing on the surface
私たちはそれを表面上では見ることができません
That's why I worked so hard to come up with this way.
だからこそ、私はこの方法を思いつくために一生懸命働きました。
to verify
検証します
so this is
それでこれは
should be the only
唯一であるべきです
I know so far
ここまでは知っています
The only person in science who does this
科学界でこれを行う唯一の人
yes
はい
Hello Mr. Lin
こんにちは、リンさん
I want to ask is in the past geological records
聞きたいのは過去の地質記録です
Is there any record of volcanic debris in the Datong volcanic group like Unzen Volcano?
雲仙火山のような大同火山群に火山れきの記録はあるのでしょうか？
In the history of our mankind, there is no
私たち人類の歴史の中で、
But in geology
しかし地質学では
If there is information, I can show you that debris road.
情報があれば、あの瓦礫の道をお見せします。
what's that called
それは何と呼ばれますか
The kind with debris in several places
ところどころにゴミが入っているタイプ
that kind of road
そういう道
We haven't decided on the land and year yet.
土地も年もまだ決まっていない。
We are now just like six thousand years is just a year of volcanic ash
今はちょうど 6,000 年前のような、まさに火山灰の年です
The land on the other side of the debris has not yet been overcome
瓦礫の向こう側の土地はまだ克服されていない
But at least there's evidence out there
しかし少なくとも証拠はある
is visible from the surface
表面から見える
yes
はい
So it is not sure whether it is possible to be as serious as Japan's self-disaster
したがって、日本の自災と同じくらい深刻になることが可能かどうかはわかりません
Are you sure you know there is such a record?
そんな記録があるのをご存知ですか？
have this record
この記録を持っています
But our human history is
しかし、私たち人類の歴史は、
In Taiwan only
台湾のみ
No more than 1000 years or so without these records
これらの記録が存在しないのはせいぜい1000年程度です
ok thank you teacher
わかりました、先生ありがとう
Hello teacher
こんにちは先生
Chase Volcanic Group
チェイス火山グループ
Because it is quite old
かなり古いものなので
More than 28 million to 200,000
2,800 万以上 200,000 まで
Recently, it was just about 50 million
最近は5000万くらいだった
5000 years
5000年
So a magma in this place
つまり、この場所にはマグマがある
Distribution of double libraries
ダブルライブラリの配布
Historically
歴史的に
Should it be concentrated
集中すればいいのに
because when it's about to spray flowers
なぜなら、花を散布しようとしているときだからです。
There must be cracks sucked out
吸い出された亀裂があるはずです
right
右
at Big Butt Volcano in this
この中のビッグバット火山で
triangle fault this period
今期の三角断層
There may also be cracks and suction that will spray out
ひび割れや吸引による吹き出しが発生する場合もあります
But the volume of the magma chamber
しかしマグマだまりの容積は
Correspondingly, it must also be sucked with crack
それに応じて、それもクラックで吸わなければなりません
have a match
試合をする
So when it comes to spraying flowers
それで、花にスプレーするときは
Is there one of these two
この2つのうちどちらかはありますか
there is a proof
証拠があります
Yes, many academic circles or our experts probably think that it means
はい、多くの学界や専門家はおそらくそれが意味するものだと考えています。
The current triangular fault
現在の三角断層
In fact, it is a bad department
実はダメな部署です
The magma is likely to be on this inferior system
マグマはこの下位星系にある可能性が高い
this climb up
この登り
It is along this line of development
この発展の流れに沿っています
the future is actually
未来は実際にある
We can't be sure
確かなことはできません
But the possibility is possible
でも可能性はあり得る
So this goes up this direction of the triangle fault
つまり、これは三角断層のこの方向に上がっていきます
Is Qiqisan right next to the fault at the foot of the mountain?
七岐山は山の麓の断層のすぐ隣ですか？
The big oil pit is not far away
大きな石油ピットは遠くない
Then we saw the verification activity
次に検証活動を見ました
That is, the seismic activity is all on the side of the Seven Seventh Three Oil Pit.
つまり、地震活動はすべて七七三油田側にあるということだ。
It seems to match the geometry of the triangle fault.
三角断層の形状と一致しているようです。
Therefore, it is very likely that the inferior system along the fault zone of the Triangular Fault
したがって、三角断層の断層帯に沿って下位システムが存在する可能性が非常に高い。
lava will come up
溶岩が出てきます
This is guesswork
これは推測です
Another inference is that
もう一つの推論は、
Because the triangular fault is a kind of fault before the earthquake
三角断層は地震前の断層の一種なので
only then will there be contact
その時のみ連絡があります
years to now
今から数年
200,000 years to the last 50 million years
20万年から過去5000万年まで
Because this time comes in the crust
今回はクラストに入ってくるので
in terms of address
住所的に
is it going to stabilize
安定するのかな
or there will be signs of activity
あるいは活動の兆候があるだろう
Is there any research on this
これに関する研究はありますか
There is a comparison problem with the magma chamber
マグマだまりとの比較に問題がある
Because if the magma chamber is on the other side
マグマだまりが向こう側にあるなら
over here over here
ここにここに
It is also impossible to have the problem of spraying flowers
花にスプレーする問題も発生しません
This is actually a good question
これは実に良い質問です
because of how we do research now
現在の研究方法のせいで
to citizen is now
市民にとっては今です
you have to compare with the past
過去と比較する必要がある
to know that it is regional stability
それが地域の安定であることを知る
still unstable
まだ不安定です
But past evidence actually
しかし実際には過去の証拠
super blurry
超ぼやけた
So we just can't compare
だから単純に比較することはできない
so many people say
とても多くの人が言う
Magma is in the process of cooling
マグマは冷却中です
Then of course nothing will happen in the future
それなら当然今後何も起こらない
still not cooling
まだ冷めていない
Evidence
証拠
good evidence to control his activities now is up and down
現在の彼の活動をコントロールする良い証拠が浮き沈みしている
yes yes yes of course
はい、はい、もちろんです
Yes Yes Yes
はいはいはい
There is still a lot of work to do after all this
このすべてが終わっても、やるべきことはまだたくさんあります
Thanks
ありがとう
Hello Professor Lin
こんにちは、リン先生
two questions
2つの質問
The first one is like our landslides
最初のものは私たちの地滑りのようなものです
When we all have to issue alerts
全員が警報を発する必要があるとき
Just say how much rainfall exceeds the yellow alert
黄色警報を超える降水量を言ってください
Or the amount of rainfall exceeds the red alert
または、降雨量が赤色警報を超えている場合
I don't know if our TVO has any data now
現在 TVO にデータがあるかどうかはわかりません
when the earthquake exceeds how much
地震がどのくらいを超えるとき
or how much the ground temperature exceeds
または地面の温度がどれくらいを超えるか
or when the concentration of carbon dioxide reaches
または二酸化炭素濃度が以下に達したとき
we're going to publish the next
次を公開する予定です
we live right under the volcanic triangle
私たちは火山の三角地帯の真下に住んでいます
we care about this stack
私たちはこのスタックを大切にしています
Then the second question is
それでは2番目の質問は、
small oil pit it
小さなオイルピットです
We now call it a blowout word
今ではそれを爆発的な言葉と呼んでいます
that it didn't stand to burst
破裂するのに耐えられなかったということ
we call it a blowout port better
私たちはそれを吹き出しポートと呼んでいます
It would be more appropriate to call it the landslide
地滑りと言った方が適切だろう
Now the second question should be the blowout
さて、2番目の質問は爆発するはずです
because of the collapse
崩壊のせいで
Collapsed
崩壊した
because most think it's a burst
ほとんどの人がバーストだと思うから
a rupture in a fault zone
断層帯の断層
That collapse behavior is not like that
その崩壊行為はそういうものではありません
collapse is just a sag
崩壊は単なるたるみです
but it is a concave whole
でも全体的に凹んでいる
like a pit
穴のような
So it's not the same as collapsing
だからそれは崩壊するのと同じではない
it's a blast
最高だよ
and we have a lot of steam
そして私たちにはたくさんの蒸気があります
what is this jet
このジェットは何ですか
the first question is
最初の質問は
next to
の隣に
this is very difficult
これはとても難しいです
but
しかし
One NCDR is the center of the international battlefield
一つのNCDRが国際戦場の中心となる
Or the Executive Yuan or the Ministry of the Interior
行政院とか内務省とか
Forced me to talk about this every day
毎日このことについて話すことを強制された
But I'm here to be honest
でも、正直に言うとここにいます
Actually, I know very little
実は私もほとんど知識がありません
But the people or the government need a standard
しかし、国民や政府には基準が必要です
So we're forced to set a standard
したがって、基準を設定する必要があります
we try very
私たちはとても努力します
because there is no history
歴史がないから
no background
背景なし
so we don't know
だから私たちには分かりません
How big is this volcano
この火山はどのくらいの大きさですか
Only then will the dam collapse
そうすればダムは決壊するだろう
if it has previous records
過去の記録がある場合
we can probably use it as a reference
おそらく参考として使用できます
But we don't have this record
しかし、私たちはこの記録を持っていません
So we can only put
したがって、私たちはただ置くことができます
compulsively put other volcanic
他の火山を強制的に置く
Many volcanoes in Japan are used as a reference
日本の多くの火山が参考にされています
But I must say that this reference is actually
しかし、この参照は実際には
really just for reference
本当に単なる参考のために
cannot
できない
Much of this is still unknown
その多くはまだ不明です
difficult things
難しいこと
Because many people are in this civil government
この民政府には多くの人がいるから
Most have been asking about this
ほとんどの人がこれについて質問しています
This is with effort
これは努力次第です
ok lady
わかりました、女性
Teacher Lin, I want to ask you
リン先生、聞きたいのですが
Because I often take Chinese and foreign tourists to small tourists
中国人や外国人観光客を小旅行者に連れていくことが多いので
I remember about half a year ago
半年ほど前のことを思い出します
There was a magnitude 5.5 earthquake this year
今年はマグニチュード5.5の地震がありました
very close to taipei
台北にとても近い
After a few days, I will take tourists to Xiaoyoukeng
数日後、観光客を小油坑に連れて行きます
I just realized I haven't gone yet
まだ行ってないことに今気づきました
as soon as i got out of the parking lot i heard
駐車場から出た瞬間に聞こえた
Loud sound like pit shooting an airplane
飛行機をピットショットするような大きな音
i never heard
聞いたことがない
then you're the first to hear
それならあなたが最初に聞いた人です
I always
私はいつも
the airport is very big
空港はとても大きいです
Because I often take Chinese and foreign tourists to that scenic spot
私はよく中国人や外国人観光客をその景勝地に連れて行きますので
I've never heard of such a big
そんな大きな話は聞いたことがない
As big as a crater plane right next to your ear
耳のすぐ横にあるクレーター面ほどの大きさ
I was thinking then
その時私は考えていました
My video should start leading everyone away
私のビデオがみんなを遠ざけ始めるはずです
escape with everyone
みんなで逃げる
But two months later
しかし2ヶ月後
when i go
僕が行く時
that voice is gone
その声は消えた
Then you often monitor over there
それからあなたはよくあそこを監視します
i don't know
わからない
This is a very common phenomenon
これは非常に一般的な現象です
it's just that loud
それだけうるさいです
The sound of your jet is different from the ones I usually go to
あなたのジェットの音は私がいつも行くものとは違う
The other one is that the information I read is that
もう一つは、私が読んだ情報は、
Two judgments whether it is a volcano
火山かどうかの2つの判断
one that you just listed
あなたが今リストしたもの
What I've read always says 200,000 years
私が読んだものにはいつも20万年と書かれています
The first condition is 200,000 years
最初の条件は20万年です
The second condition is whether there is a magma chamber
2つ目の条件はマグマ​​だまりがあるかどうか
Then I know that we now know that there are magma chambers.
そしてマグマだまりがあることがわかったということです。
Said that we used to define it as repairing volcanoes or even stone volcanoes
私たちはそれを火山や石火山の修復と定義していたと言いました
Then I also read about Guishan Island
それから亀山島についても読みました。
The last eruption appears to have been 200,000 years ago
最後の噴火は20万年前だったようだ
four times
四回
Then I want to know the dating method that says I am more correct
だったらもっと正しいと言える出会い方を知りたい
i should say
言うべきだ
which one should be used
どちらを使用すべきか
which was the last eruption
それが最後の噴火でした
Because I obviously 200,000 is not the same
明らかに20万は同じじゃないから
200,000 is not
20万ではない
ten thousand years
一万年
10,000 years is actually related to the Central Geological Survey
1万年は実は中央地質調査所と関係がある
active fault
活断層
That is, the most active active fault is 10,000 years old.
つまり、最も活発な活断層は1万年前のものです。
So ten thousand years is them
それで一万年ですか
In the geological world, they are equivalent to having a
地質学の世界では、それらは
as long as it is a living geology
それが生きた地質である限り
Regardless of volcanic faults, all are references
火山断層に関係なく、すべてが参考になります
Two hundred thousand is too long
20万は長すぎる
The two hundred thousand...
二十万は…
And you just heard that I really hope
そして、あなたは今聞いたばかりですが、私は本当に願っています
if you can take your time
お時間をいただければ
probably tell me
おそらく教えてください
Because we now have a 24 hour record
24時間の記録が残っているので
Then if you probably have the truth
それで、もしあなたがおそらく真実を知っているとしたら
how often do you say
どのくらいの頻度で言いますか
In my impression, I watched it carefully for half a year
半年じっくり観た感想としては
i spent a lot of time
たくさんの時間を費やしました
20 hour inspection
20時間検査
About 10 days on average
平均10日程度
two weeks
二週間
Anyway, about 10 days or so
とりあえず10日くらいかな
I can probably argue
たぶん議論できる
There is the sound of this so-called place name
このいわゆる地名の響きがあります
But sometimes very often
でも時々とても頻繁に
Sometimes it's 3 days
3日の場合もあります
always have
いつももっている
that sometimes happens sporadically
それは時々散発的に起こります
Just once or twice a week
週に1、2回だけ
Dirty, right?
汚いですよね？
so if you can really hear
それで本当に聞こえるなら
Because I often ask people
人によく聞くので
Because of my information, I saw that it really exists.
情報のおかげで、それが本当に存在することが分かりました。
but i didn't really hear anyone
でも本当に誰にも聞こえなかった
So you probably have this very precious
だからあなたはおそらくこれを非常に貴重なものを持っているでしょう
is that I believe he usually looks like
彼は普段次のように見えると思います
just pissed off
ただ怒っているだけ
But occasionally found that there will be something like
しかし、時々、次のようなものがあることがわかります
like firecrackers
爆竹のように
loud this
大声でこれ
popping sound
パチパチ音
Otherwise, you will not receive my earthquake
そうしないと、私の地震が受信できなくなります
yes yes that should be
はい、そうあるべきです
because what you describe is
なぜならあなたが説明しているのは
it is relatively low frequency
比較的低い周波数です
a little longer
もう少し
right right right right
右右右右
wow this is real
うわー、これは本物です
yes
はい
if the volcano
火山なら
fire volcano it can come in fire volcano
火の火山、火の火山に入ることができます
can there be a way
方法はありますか
can it be made into a stone volcano
石の火山にできるでしょうか
right
右
because it's on a volcano
火山の上だから
while it's working
それが働いている間
we invest something in
私たちは何かに投資します
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
then to destroy it
それからそれを破壊するために
volcanic stuff
火火山的東西
This, this, this is a bit difficult
これ、これ、ちょっと難しいです
This is like an earthquake. Some people say that the energy of Zhentan is lost.
これは地震のようなもので、鎮丹のエネルギーが失われると言う人もいます。
So this fault
それでこのギャップは
He just wanted to say we just let it make a small earthquake
彼はただ、小さな地震を起こさせるだけだと言いたかっただけです
A big earthquake turns into many small earthquakes
大きな地震が起こると、小さな地震がたくさん起こります。
we water it
私たちはそれに水をやります
This is a scientific quake
これは科学的な地震です
Fault you pump water into it
ポンプで水を注入したせいだ
it will start to slip
滑り始めます
release energy
エネルギーを解放する
But this is very risky
しかし、これは非常に危険です
no one dares to do this why
なぜ誰もそんなことをしようとしないのですか
How to do it?
どうやってするの？
Yes, yes, it is fine normally
はい、はい、普通に大丈夫です
you add water to it
あなたはそれに水を加えます
That's it, a big earthquake, who is responsible
それは大地震、責任は誰ですか
This is actually
これは実際には
You can't control whether it will increase or decrease
増えるか減るかはコントロールできない
The same problem is that the volcano
同じ問題は火山です。
the natural world i think we
自然界は私たちだと思う
probably difficult
おそらく難しい
With current technology it is possible
現在の技術ではそれが可能です
is it possible
出来ますか
how to do this
これを行う方法
if i stand over there
私がそこに立っていれば
how could he want to go
彼はどうやって行きたいのでしょう
He works or stands there
彼はそこで働いているか、そこに立っている
Because the magma chamber is over there.
あそこにマグマだまりがあるから。
Yes Yes Yes
はいはいはい
it would have been a big thing
それは大変なことだったでしょう
We can slowly reduce it
徐々に減らしていくことができる
replace it with this
これに置き換えてください
If the line is like this, that's right.
このような線であれば、そうです。
It should be possible
それは可能なはずです
But now I don't know what to do
でも今は何をしたらいいのか分からない
yes
はい
Okay, Professor Lin, ask for advice.
わかりました、リン教授、アドバイスをお願いします。
That is to say you just mentioned
つまり、今おっしゃった
Huangchi Park is a huge volcano
黄池公園は巨大な火山です
so-called extra-large or medium-sized
いわゆる特大または中型
or how a small volcano is defined
または小さな火山がどのように定義されるか
So how dangerous is it?
それで、それはどれくらい危険ですか？
Probably we can now easily define
おそらく今では簡単に定義できるでしょう
just look at it
それを見てください
Like this volume of the magma house
マグマハウスのこの巻のように
It seems like the one in Huangchi Park
黄池公園にあるもののようです
Seems like thousands of cubic kilometers
数千立方キロメートルに見える
A few thousand, I don't know if fifteen thousand or how much
数千、1万5千か、それともいくらかはわかりません
That's just like ours
それはまさに私たちと同じです
The big round volcano may only be
大きな丸い火山は、
Only a hundred
たったの百
About 100 programs
約100プログラム
Of course it's the magma house
もちろんマグマハウスです
The bigger the magma chamber, it only needs to be squeezed out a little bit, which is actually quite impressive
マグマだまりが大きいほど、少し絞り出している限り、実際には非常に印象的です
If the magma chamber is small, of course it is less dangerous
マグマだまりが小さければ、もちろん危険は少ない
So volcanoes are graded
火山には等級が付けられている
According to the magma, it is divided into 12345 levels
マグマによると、12345のレベルに分かれています
graded
段階的
Just now I saw a few after the volcanic eruption
たった今、火山の噴火後にいくつか見ました
There is an example of escaping
逃げた例もある
Then I want to ask that after the volcano ceases to be active
そこで聞きたいのは、火山の活動が終わった後についてです。
How soon can they go back and live there
彼らはどれくらい早く戻ってそこに住むことができますか
wow this is another problem
うわー、これは別の問題です
In fact, it is relatively easy for people to evacuate from the volcano
実際、火山が人々を避難させるのは比較的簡単です。
And after the evacuation, when will they be allowed to go back
そして避難後、いつ戻ることが許可されるのでしょうか
People in general always want to go back
一般の人はいつも戻りたいと思っています
Looks like as long as it doesn't smoke, he wants to go back
煙が出ない限り、彼は戻りたいようです
But the role unit, the government is actually very difficult
しかし、政府という役割単位は実際には非常に難しいです
Because what I just talked about is when the magma goes up
なぜなら、私が今話したのはマグマが上昇するときのことだからです。
We can easily see those
それらを簡単に確認できます
But he stringed to a certain word
しかし彼はある言葉をつなぎ合わせた
Then it started when there was no change
その後、何も変化がなかったときに始まりました
When will it suddenly come together again?
いつになったらまた突然集まるんだろう？
that the evidence starts to get murky.
証拠が曖昧になり始めるということ。
even say when it will start to be quiet
いつ静かになり始めるかさえ言う
This is not a good reference standard
これは適切な参照基準ではありません
Sometimes it is one of the decision-making units
場合によっては、意思決定単位の 1 つとなることもあります
it's just a decision
それは単なる決断です
So going back is actually a big trouble
だから戻るのは実際には大きな問題だ
when can we go back
いつ戻れますか
like hawaii, right?
ハワイみたいですよね？
move at midnight
真夜中に移動する
then it seems to stop
そしたら止まりそうです
recently again
最近またまた
like that paris island
あのパリ島のように
Last October was like two months of activity
昨年の 10 月は 2 か月ほどの活動でした
Then it stops in the middle
そうすると途中で止まってしまいます
That July the last July
あの7月 去年の7月
Paris Island is back in action
パリ島が活動を再開
So when he first moved
それで彼が最初に引っ越したとき
That kind of estimation is actually more difficult.
この種の推定は実際にはさらに困難です。
But from being quiet to moving
しかし、静かな状態から動く状態へ
It's actually easier
実際はもっと簡単です
from hole to silence
穴から沈黙へ
that is
あれは
not so easy
そう簡単ではない
so still
まだ
want a lot
たくさん欲しい
lady behind
後ろの女性
i want to ask
聞きたいです
That researcher Lin is
その研究者リンは
Because I told you a long time ago
ずっと前に言ったから
Earthquakes can be predicted with animals
動物で地震を予知できる
like a fish or a snake or something
魚か蛇か何かのように
But have you ever thought about using animals to
しかし、動物を使って何かをすることを考えたことはありますか?
conduct
行為
i don't know maybe you're not very practical either
わかりませんが、あなたもあまり現実的ではないかもしれません
but maybe there is a way
でも、もしかしたら方法があるかもしれない
Have you ever been through this period?
この時期を経験したことがありますか？
still have you thought about it
まだ考えていますか
this is not bad
これは悪くない
Why do we use animals for earthquakes
なぜ地震に動物を使うのか
in what strange way
何という奇妙な方法で
Because the science of earthquake prediction
地震予知の科学だから
upper level of science
科学の上級レベル
Everyone thinks it's not feasible
誰もがそれは無理だと思っている
so everyone is
だからみんなそうだよ
If you go to Western medicine
西洋医学に行くなら
I found out that you are terminally ill and cannot be cured.
あなたが末期の病気で、治すことができないことがわかりました。
Then everyone is looking for a way
それからみんなが方法を探しています
But in terms of volcanoes
しかし、火山に関して言えば、
He talks to you about the science chapter
彼は科学の章について話します
There is a lot of evidence that volcanoes cost money to erupt
火山の噴火には費用がかかるという多くの証拠がある
Why should I look for a remedy?
なぜ治療法を探す必要があるのでしょうか?
So in terms of volcanoes
火山の言葉で言えば
You do these monitoring for formal evidence
正式な証拠のためにこれらのモニタリングを行います
probably the answer
おそらく答え
But the earthquake is still touching
しかし、地震はまだ続いています
So the idea of thousands or hundreds of dollars will come out
それで数千ドル、数百ドルというアイデアが出てくるでしょう
Thanks
ありがとう
I want to confirm one thing with your professor
教授に一つ確認したいことがあります
A few months ago in Beitou there was an earthquake at more than four o'clock
数か月前、北投で午後4時過ぎに地震がありました。
Exactly the same result when I saw
見たときと全く同じ結果でした
It seems to be near Zhongshan Building
中山ビルの近くにあるようです
It's very close to the Tatun Volcanic Group
大屯火山群のすぐ近くです
Later, the Meteorological Bureau said that it was due to the movement of the plate.
その後、気象庁はプレートの移動によるものだと発表した。
but i doubt it
しかし私はそれを疑います
so according to your opinion
だからあなたの意見によれば
The earthquake caused by the same thing
同じ事で起きた地震
Is it really a plate movement?
それは本当にプレートの動きですか？
It is also a post-increase of the volcanic group
それは火山群の増加後でもあります
if i remember correctly
もし私が正確に覚えていれば
you may be asking to have a
を求めているかもしれません
They called it the Beitou Earthquake at first
最初は北投地震と呼ばれていました
right
右
This scale is 5.7
このスケールは5.7です
because for many years
なぜなら長年にわたって
There is no earthquake that happened in the center of Taipei City
台北市中心部で地震は起きていない
The earthquake was actually
地震は実際にあった
The weather should be right.
天気は良いはずだ。
The reason is that the earthquake was deep
理由は地震が深かったから
more than 100 kilometers
100キロ以上
So that is related to our Philippine Sea plate
つまり、それはフィリピン海プレートに関係しているということです
go north in silence
黙って北へ行く
Earthquakes in this hidden belt
この隠れた帯での地震
It's not in this 10km of the volcano
火山のこの10km圏内にはありません
this shallow surface
この浅い表面
If it is within 5 km 10 km
5km以内の場合は10km
That's more to do with volcanoes
それはむしろ火山と関係があります
but is it 140 or what
でも140なのか何なのか
140 kilometers
140キロ
that's deep
それは深いです
It is related to the plate
プレート関連です
So the Meteorological Bureau's interpretation is
つまり気象庁の解釈は、
basically ok
基本的には大丈夫です
It is scientifically accepted
科学的に認められている
right
右
sir behind
後ろの先生
Hello Mr. Lin
こんにちは、リンさん
What We Know About the Threat of Volcanoes in Northern Taiwan
台湾北部の火山の脅威について私たちが知っていること
In addition to the big hip volcano
大きなヒップ火山に加えて
haiti volcano in geelung it is also a volcano of fire
ハイチの基隆火山は火の火山でもあります
And it may have been active in Keelung Sea School in 1867
そして1867年には基隆海洋学校で活動していた可能性があります
Will we address such disaster risks in the future?
将来的にはこのような災害リスクに対処できるのでしょうか？
will do some scientific research
いくつかの科学的研究をするでしょう
Thanks
ありがとう
Yes, I'm personally very interested
はい、個人的にとても興味があります
You are actually many, many professional
あなたは本当にたくさんのプロフェッショナルです
Because there is a seabed and a volcano directly below Keelung Port.
基隆港の真下には海底と火山があるからです。
submarine volcano
海底火山
And they went to explore the ocean
そして彼らは海を探検しに行きました
That volcanic sea will be very steamy
その火山海はとても蒸し暑いでしょう
It means it's a volcano
つまり火山です
The teacher Xi Jinping from CUHK and the teacher from Yangshan National Taiwan University
香港大学の習近平先生と国立台湾大学陽山先生
they just do some research
彼らはただ研究をしているだけです
Then I also believe
それなら私も信じます
I personally believe this to be proven
個人的にはこれが証明されていると信じています
It was the sea school in 1867
1867年には海洋学校でした
It is probably because it was said in the early days that the sea school caused by the earthquake
地震による海の学校は初期に言われてたからでしょうね
But the volcanic, submarine volcanic activity caused the sea school
しかし、火山、海底火山活動により海の学校が発生しました。
In fact, the possibility is quite high
実はその可能性はかなり高い
but need evidence
でも証拠が必要だ
that we need to investigate
調査する必要があること
So the future government will also do this
だから将来の政府もそうするだろう
I personally will be very involved in doing it
私個人としてもそれに深く関わっていきます
It's just that the investigation and research in the sea is more difficult
ただ海での調査・研究はより困難です
So we need more of these technologies
したがって、これらのテクノロジーがさらに必要です
or some way to overcome
または何らかの克服方法
but that's worth doing
でもそれはやる価値がある
yes
はい
Literary performance
文学パフォーマンス
Hello teacher
こんにちは先生
two questions
2つの質問
The first question is about the prediction of volcanic eruptions
第一問目は火山噴火の予知についてです。
It's what you just mentioned
それはあなたが今言ったことです
If you try to predict a volcanic eruption
火山の噴火を予測しようとすると
We can see that it was before the earthquake
地震前だったことがわかります
It is possible to slowly change forward from a relatively deep place
比較的深い場所からゆっくりと前方にチェンジすることが可能
Then but what I want to ask is
それで、でも聞きたいのは、
The speed at which the magma is extruded from the ground
マグマが地面から押し出される速度
how fast it can
どれくらい早くできるか
Like if a whole bunch of omens happened within two hours today
まるで今日の2時間以内にたくさんの前兆が起こったかのように
Like some hot spring water getting hot
温泉水が熱くなるみたいに
or place names
地名とか
just too helpless
無力すぎる
could it be in two hours
2時間以内でしょうか
maybe or a
たぶん、あるいは
Within this hour, all earthquake-prone people will be
この 1 時間以内に、地震が発生しやすい土地に住むすべての人が、
Then the water temperature of the hot springs and the like
それから温泉の湯温など
Is it possible to have such a fast speed
そんなに速いスピードが出せるのか
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
Excuse me
すみません
And then the second question is about the crater lake
そして2番目の質問はその火口湖についてです
It's what I read in a magazine
雑誌で読んだ内容です
There are three three crater lakes in Africa
アフリカには三大火口湖が３つある
Then what used to happen was
それから、かつて何が起こっていたかというと、
It's the volcano under the crater lake.
火口湖の下にある火山です。
gas eruption
ガス噴火
which then creates carbon dioxide in the lake
その後、湖で二酸化炭素が発生します
concentration saturation etc.
濃度飽和など
And then this carbon dioxide floats out of this lake
そしてこの二酸化炭素がこの湖から漂ってきます
and killed an entire village in one night
そして一晩で村全体を殺した
Then what I want to ask is
そこで聞きたいのは、
Is it possible for this to happen in Taiwan?
台湾でもこんな事が起きる可能性はあるのでしょうか？
because we just heard
ちょうど聞いたばかりなので
That is, Taiwan has Haitian volcanoes.
つまり、台湾にはハイチの火山があるのです。
There are many hot springs
温泉もたくさんあるし
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
Is it because Taiwan has this condition that this kind of thing will happen?
台湾がこのような条件を備えているから、このようなことが起こるのでしょうか？
that's it thank you
それはそれで、ありがとう
Yes Yes
はいはい
The first question is to say
最初の質問はこう言います
because one hour two hours
1時間2時間だから
Suddenly the volcano erupts
突然火山が噴火した
basically it should be hard
基本的には難しいはずです
Because the magma is actually very viscous when it moves.
マグマが動くとき、実際には非常に粘性が高いからです。
It will not run from 5km to 10km to the surface like a bomb
爆弾のように地表まで5kmから10kmを走ることはありません。
can't be that fast
そんなに速くはできない
Usually weeks or months
通常、数週間または数か月
even for several years
たとえ数年間であっても
it's running slowly
ゆっくり走っています
So within a short period of time, probably within a day
したがって、短期間のうちに、おそらく 1 日以内に
It should be from the school ceremony, but there is no
入学式のはずですが、ありません
about crater lake
火口湖について
In fact, because it is full of your volcano
実際、そこはあなたの火山でいっぱいだから
there is a crater
クレーターがある
like a lake
湖のように
Then it will rain and a lot of water will accumulate
その後雨が降って大量の水が溜まる
That volcanic gas is actually a lot of acid
あの火山ガスは実は酸が多いんです
And CO2 is the most
そしてCO2が一番多い
There is also a lot of acid
酸もたっぷりです
So these can easily become sour
なので酸っぱくなりやすいです
Carbonic acid, fluidic acid, etc.
炭酸、流動酸など
Of course, the same is true for plant organisms or animals.
もちろん、植物や動物についても同様です。
quite a big impact
かなり大きな影響
so you just have to be in crater lake
だからあなたはクレーター湖にいればいいのです
if there is volcanic activity
火山活動がある場合
In fact, the water will become very acidic.
実際、水は非常に酸性になります。
will affect
影響するだろう
But under the sea
でも海の下では
This problem may be less
この問題は少なくなるかもしれません
Because the sea is water after all, it is big
海はやっぱり水だから大きいですね
so it gets diluted
だから薄まってしまう
But the lake has very little water
しかし、湖には水がほとんどありません
So it will be relatively high concentration
なので比較的高濃度になります
will be more harmful
より有害になるだろう
The sea is probably unless it happens to be in a submarine crater
海はおそらく、海底クレーター内でない限り、
Creatures there may be affected
そこにいる生き物が影響を受ける可能性があります
But it's easy to dilute
でも薄めるのは簡単
yes
はい
There's another one here
ここにもう一つあります
Hello teacher
こんにちは先生
What about Chase Volcano?
チェイス・ボルケーノはどうですか？
Our date according to the Volcano Society is
火山協会によると、私たちの日付は次のとおりです。
The last climb was within a few thousand years
最後の登頂は数千年以内だった
then ask the teacher
それから先生に聞いてください
The date of the volcanic meeting is
火山会議の日は
probably what kind of method
おそらくどのような方法でしょうか
may the teacher explain
先生が説明してくださいますか
volcano will it actually be
火山は本当にそうなるのだろうか
Simple, they all use a lot
シンプルでどれもよく使います
carbon fourteen its some half-life
炭素 14 の半減期
So many address circles use half-life
非常に多くのアドレス サークルが半減期を使用しています
then it is a decay how many years it takes
それなら何年かかりますか？
Then see that the ratio has decayed several times
次に、比率が数回減衰していることを確認します。
then how many years
それから何年
It's probably like this for many years
たぶん何年もこんな感じ
Just use the half-life of the earth year
地球の一年の半減期を使えばいいだけ
The half-life of course
半減期は当然
Carbon fourteen is often used for thousands of years to ten thousand years
炭素 14 は、数千年から 1 万年にわたってよく使用されます。
But if it's hundreds of thousands of years or millions
でもそれが何十万年か何百万年だったら
It has additionally this radiological accreditation
さらにこの放射線学的認定も取得しています
That can already be made dumb or dumb or something like that
それはもうバカにするかバカにするか、そのようなものにすることができます
So they have professionals who are doing this
彼らにはこれを行う専門家がいます
Yes Yes Yes
はいはいはい
Is it okay, here is the last one
いいですか、これで最後です
last question
最後一個問題
yes
はい
I just want to ask
ただ聞きたいのですが
Can the volcanic crushed crab flow predict the direction?
火山によって砕かれたカニの流れは方向を予測できるのでしょうか?
Because at that time Pompeii would be
なぜなら、その頃ポンペイは
will be submerged by the volcanic shardcrab flow
火山の破片の流れによって水没するだろう
That is, it goes in that direction
つまり、その方向に進むということです
In addition, there is another Napoleon director's place
さらに、もう一つナポレオン監督の場所があります
If it's distributed at the Datong event in Taipei
台北の大同イベントで頒布する場合
Can we just predict which direction it's going?
それがどの方向に進むかを予測することはできますか?
Then we can avoid that disaster
そうすれば、私たちはその災害を避けることができます
yes the answer is yes
はい、答えははいです
It's as simple as water
それは水と同じくらい簡単です
you pour the water down
あなたは水を注ぎます
it goes to the lowest flow
それは一番低い流れに行きます
that's actually for this
それは実際にはこのためです
In fact, Japan, especially Japan, has done a lot of work
実際、日本、特に日本は多くの取り組みを行ってきました。
It looks at the village for example
たとえば村を見てみましょう
That, that, that ancient underground is a village
あの、あの、古代の地下は村です
then what do they do
それで彼らは何をしますか
That that water spilled into the sea and rushed to the village
その水が海に溢れて村に押し寄せたということ
they do something like this
彼らはこのようなことをします
gutter or retaining wall
側溝または擁壁
It's a bit like the concept of flood control
治水の概念に似ています
Just be a very, very resolute body
とても、とても毅然とした体でいてください
When the water leaks and touches that body, it turns a corner.
水が漏れてそのボディに触れるとコーナーを曲がります。
won't rush to the village
急いで村に行かないだろう
So this is predictable
だからこれは予想通りだよ
predictable
予測可能な
Then make some preparations for evacuation
それから避難の準備をしましょう
So Japan has done a lot in this regard
この点に関して日本は多くのことを行ってきた
Thanks
ありがとう
i want to end
終わりたい
Let us know about our August
8月の様子をお知らせします
Feast of knowledge next month
来月は知識の饗宴
by Chen Zhicheng
陳志成著
is the biomedical
生物医学です
Institute of Science
科学研究所
What's the matter with soreness?
痛みはどうしたの？
So this is a life science subject
これは生命科学の科目です
talk about pain slowly
痛みについてゆっくり話す
molecular biology
分子生物学
receptor molecule with acid
酸を持つ受容体分子
that's there
それはそこにあります
before we all get ready to leave
みんなで出発の準備をする前に
let us once again warmly
もう一度暖かくしましょう
Thank you for your wonderful speech today
今日は素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
Thank you all for coming
お越しいただきありがとうございました
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Related here, is any of the said related.
ここで関連するのは、上記のいずれかです。